<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	<!-- generator="WordPress/6.6.2" created="2024-10-28 04:28" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>The Aggie Transcript</title>
	<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu</link>
	<description>An undergraduate life sciences journal at UC Davis</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 04:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://www.faculty.ucdavis.edu/</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu</wp:base_blog_url>

		<wp:author><wp:author_id>651</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[bghayoumi@ucdavis.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Aggie Transcript]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Bardia]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Ghayoumi]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>30</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[sburgess]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[smburgess@ucdavis.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Sean Burgess]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Sean]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Burgess]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>822</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[rmhull]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[rmhull@ucdavis.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[rmhull]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>911</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[blbahn]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[blbahn@ucdavis.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[blbahn]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1218</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[wusarah]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[ssjwu@ucdavis.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[wusarah]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Sarah]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Wu]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

		<wp:category>
		<wp:term_id>291</wp:term_id>
		<wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[campus-news-and-reports]]></wp:category_nicename>
		<wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent>
		<wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></wp:cat_name>
	</wp:category>
				
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2018/06/cropped-clear_logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>The Aggie Transcript</title>
	<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 

		<item>
		<title><![CDATA["Let’s Take a Deep Breath":           Managing Hypertension by Bridging the Clinic-Home Healthcare Gap]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/lets-take-a-deep-breath-managing-hypertension-by-bridging-the-clinic-home-healthcare-gap/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.wordpress.com/?p=891</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Independent Project Findings

By Harsh Sharma,  Neurobiology, Physiology, and Behavior, '13

Author's Note:
<p style="padding-left:30px">"I wrote this paper to share my independent project takeaways with everyone who is interested in, or a part of, the healthcare field. This project taught me a lot about what we can do to help our patients get the most out of the clinic they go to. As you gain experiences in the medical field, think about the services your organization offers and how you can use your skills to enhance those services to the next level!"</p>
<!--more-->

<b>Background</b>

My Community HealthCorps experience at LifeLong East Oakland, a federally qualified community health center, can be described as a tale of two halves. During the first half, I accompanied Brigitte Peltekof, LifeLong’s social worker, on home visits in the East Bay Area.

I slowly learned to conduct an entire home visit by observing Brigitte. This entailed asking patients about the different social determinants of health– housing, income, transportation, caregiver support, and psychosocial history, to name a few. We then used this information to help patients access the health and social services they needed.

Amassing patient interactions over 5 months gave me the confidence to pursue an independent project centered around home visits during the second half of my term. Without having worked out the details, I chose to make high blood pressure, or hypertension, the main focus of my project for several reasons. I primarily recognized its many eventual consequences, including damage to the arteries, brain aneurysm, and kidney failure. I hoped to raise awareness of high blood pressure’s life-threatening effects to our hypertensive patients.

My time at LifeLong leading up to the project also made me aware of the barriers patients face in coming to the clinic. By meeting patients where they live, my hope for this project was to make healthcare as accessible as possible for the patients involved.

<b>Project Vision</b>

I had three goals in mind when proposing this project. They are as follows:
<ol>
 	<li>To provide the panel of patients with blood pressure cuffs and encourage a greater level of engagement in their well-being by monitoring their blood pressure and exercising daily.</li>
 	<li>To instruct patients about no-cost, easy-to-perform breathing and energy exercises intended to elicit the relaxation response via regularly scheduled home and clinic visits.</li>
</ol>
Evidence by Stahl et al. 2015 (in “Relaxation Response and Resiliency Training and Its Effect on Healthcare Resource Utilization”) states that “mind body interventions can reduce individual disease burden as well as the utilization of healthcare resources and are well suited to the changing healthcare environment.”
<ol start="3">
 	<li>To reduce patient's’ blood pressure readings by encouraging the integration of</li>
</ol>
breathing and energy exercises into their daily lives.

<b>Home Visits</b>

I began visiting patients at the end of January once I received the shipment of blood pressure monitors and finalized an initial panel of patients. During our first visit, patients signed a consent form, were educated about the consequences of hypertension and guidelines for blood pressure numbers, and agreed to a list of responsibilities as part of their participation in this panel.

Patients were provided with a blood pressure log at the beginning of each subsequent home visit to enter the date, time, and blood pressure recording, along with comments about how they felt and if they had taken their medication that day. The previous blood pressure log was collected and uploaded into the patient’s medical record. I measured the patient’s blood pressure during the visit and recorded it in the log.

Home visits also entailed asking how the patient was doing. This led to conversations about the patient’s family, home environment, level of physical activity, concerns about a medication’s side effects, and more. Before leaving, I scheduled my next visit with the patients to increase the likelihood of maintaining regular visits.

This project’s initial focus was to parse out three breathing exercises during each home visit, so as to not frontload the patients with too much information at once. The breathing exercises are often utilized in yoga (including chair yoga), energy medicine, and meditation. Most patients discovered their blood pressure to be significantly lower after engaging in breathing exercises for 5 minutes. While some patients looked forward to learning a new set of breathing exercises during each home visit, some wished to focus their efforts on a select few.

Patients who, at first, had only been interested in learning additional breathing exercises also started to utilize me as a health coach. They wanted to know when their next doctor’s appointment was, how they could switch providers, whether they were taking their medication correctly, etc. They recognized the value of having someone from the clinic come to their home and took full advantage of my service. Some patients asked me to prepare a handout about diabetic neuropathy, come up with a week-long menu of health meals, help schedule a dentist appointment, and so on. Electronic versions of all handouts can be found at: http://tinyurl.com/HTNproject

As a result, these home visits took an unexpected but welcoming change. I was now indirectly addressing hypertension by helping patients with their other chronic conditions and overall well-being. Considering that most patients on the panel, and the community in general, are alone during the day time, having someone to talk to and listen to them became refreshingly therapeutic.

<b>Patient Q &amp; A’s</b>

During my penultimate home visit, I asked each patient twelve questions about this project. Patient interviews were recorded and subsequently transcribed. Below is a paraphrased summary of the Q &amp;A. You will find the questions and assortment of answers provided by the patients at the end of this paper.

Patient takeaways from this project included awareness about the importance of getting in a relaxed state of mind while taking their blood pressure. Deborah S. spoke of the stark difference between taking her blood pressure with the TV on and off. The latter allowed her to reach a more calm state, which resulted in a lower blood pressure reading. Jarvis J. reflected on the project as a life-changing experience that improved his other health conditions and uplifted his overall sense of well-being.

Patients provided insightful suggestions on how this project could be improved. One suggestion was to go on a walk instead of having home visits, so as to provide patients with a change of environment. Linda S. suggested holding a monthly group meeting at the clinic so panelists could engage with one another and exchange successes and challenges.

When asked about what advice she would give about blood pressure, Willie B. offered that blood pressure plays a significant role in affecting quality of life as one ages. Kris D. advised individuals to focus on taking care of themselves and keeping stress to a minimum. She admitted that making time for herself is something she needs to work on, but she recognizes how important it is in maintaining a healthy blood pressure.

Most patients resoundingly wished their healthcare provider to know that this program should continue. I worked with patients who predominantly spend their time at home, alone. Home visits gave them an opportunity to socialize and talk to someone, which is powerfully therapeutic in itself.

<b>Reflections</b>

I have been deeply humbled by the patients I have had the honor of serving. I admire my patients’ courage to own up to their health conditions and their willpower to commit to improving their health. I am moved by their openness to invite a stranger into their home again and again. Their vulnerability in sharing their fears, hopes, strengths, and successes inspires me. I have seen them grow into individuals who are more invested in taking care of their health and more knowledgeable about how to do so. By spending countless hours with them, I have become a better listener and patient advocate. I have experienced tremendous personal growth from hearing their incredible stories and helping them navigate through our healthcare system. I will carry the lessons I have learned from them throughout my medical career and beyond. I want to thank them for their hospitality, their time, and their willingness to change.

By experiencing patients’ inquisitive nature toward health-related topics and their need for assistance with navigating our healthcare system (making appointments, asking about referrals, etc.), I am convinced that this project should continue to exist.

Patients who have someone that they can spend their time with in the community, without any significant time restrictions, receive a rich layer of individualized patient care and experience greater patient satisfaction. They are also more likely to utilize their clinic’s services and be intrinsically motivated to pursue a better state of health.

<b>Moving Forward</b>

Based on the feedback from patients and agreement from LifeLong staff, I firmly recommend that a project like this become a commonplace feature of our clinics. Having Health Coach Volunteers would allow clinics to do just that. Better yet, all parties involved would benefit from such a program.

Volunteers, who would mostly be future or concurrent applicants to medical and other health professional schools, would stand to gain an unparalleled experience working with the underserved on a 1-on-1 basis. They would have the opportunity to identify a patient panel and follow it over several months. Health coach volunteers would create patient education materials, shadow social workers and providers, and gain a strong letter of recommendation. Not only will their experience give them an edge in their applications to professional or graduate schools, but it also will deepen their understanding of how healthcare works and increase their maturity as they continue on their path to becoming future healthcare professionals.

If you would like to implement a similar program at your clinic, do not hesitate to contact me at sharmaharsh91@gmail.com. I will be happy to provide you with the appropriate resources.

<hr />

<b>Extended Patient Q &amp; A's
</b>
<ol>
 	<li>What has motivated you to be a part of this project?</li>
</ol>
<i>“Blood pressure issues. Newly discovered BP [blood pressure] issues.” –Susan B.</i>
<ol start="2">
 	<li>Before I started doing home/clinic visits, what did you think this project would be like?</li>
</ol>
<i>“I didn’t really know. I just, um, was like ‘hey, [they’re] just trying to see...’ I was really wanting to learn things to help me de-stress my body and that was my main concern of how to get this blood pressure down. Because even though I went through a process of losing weight before, I still had high blood pressure. So, it wasn’t just my weight, it was also the stress levels that I carry in my body.” -Kris D.</i>
<ol start="3">
 	<li>When I started doing home/clinic visits, how did these expectations change? Was it for the better or worse?</li>
</ol>
<i>“It was for the better. I’ve noticed that my BP has gone down. Like, the last time I checked it was like 121/79, which was never, ever the case. And I think that has to do with the fact that I started eating more vegetables, and taking time to jot down my BP, be more careful in doing the breathing techniques as well...and turning off the TV while taking my BP. I think that’s #1. Because before I would do it with the TV on and be more in tune with that and I think because I take time to just relax, breathe, and not have anything interfere helped.” -Deborah S.</i>
<ol start="4">
 	<li>Now that the project is coming to a close, how would you reflect on it?</li>
</ol>
<i>“A life-changing experience. With the way my BP was, it was just a matter of time before I had a stroke or...or something else could occur from it, but since I been in the program, all the testing that I’ve been doing for other things that I’ve been coming to the doctor for has just been beautiful. You know, I think my BP being kept at where it’s supposed to be kept at makes the other things work even properly without even me knowing it, since I’m not a doctor. But I can just feel the difference. You know, I’m not walking around with my head just feeling heavy. Like if you touch it, your head’s about ready to explode. You know, I was walking around like that for quite some time. And it was time for me to wake up and you guys woke me up to see that my life mattered.” -Jarvis J.</i>
<ol start="5">
 	<li>How could this project have been better?</li>
</ol>
<i>“Well, we could’ve started the walking earlier. You know, going for a walk when I visit, we could’ve started that earlier. But other than that, it’s...it’s great. But I think I like the out visit more than I do the in-home like, you know going out walking with you and then going over the things...because it’s just, I don’t know, you take it in better I think. Because when you’re in home, you’re just...it’s like okay, hurry up and finish. But walking the lake [Merritt] made it like, okay, you know, we gotta walk anyway, so why not talk and do, yeah.” -Deborah S.</i>

<i>“If we had did it in a...I don’t know...group would be all right to see what other people is do- ing. Sitting around, talking about what can be done better. I’d like to know if other people were benefiting, besides me with the program. If we got in a group, we could talk about it, and see what we could do better.” -Linda H.</i>
<ol start="6">
 	<li>What would make it easier for you or other patients to be compliant?</li>
</ol>
<i>“Be serious about it. Everything that I’ve done at the clinic, I’ve taken as seriously. And I realize that everything that happens there, which has been, you know... given to me, has been a help.” -Gloria R.</i>
<ol start="7">
 	<li>If you had to give patients who are in your shoes advice about BP, what would you tell them?</li>
</ol>
<i>“That eating actually is really...you know, eating the right stuff, eating vegetables and exercising has a lot to do with your BP, too. So taking time out to do that. And, just make sure you eat right, exercise, and do breathing techniques. I didn’t think the breathing techniques would work, but they do. They really put your mind at ease.” -Deborah S.</i>

<i>“I’d tell em it was very important for them to know what their BP is because that’s kind of determining what their quality of life is gonna be in the future.” -Willie ‘Delphine’ B.</i>

<i>“Pay attention. Pay very close attention because it’s something that can change, you know, without you being aware of it. That’s why they call BP the silent killer.” -Susan B.</i>

<i>“Don’t stress...don’t stress. Stress is a silent killer and I’ve been told that by a physician at LifeLong. Even though I’ve been told that and I try not to stress...I think once I get through my challenges of school and other things, I’m gonna really work harder on taking care of me. And I told that to my daughter and a friend that I wanted to take more time, um, taking care of me now. Because I’ve given my all to other things except for me, and I wanna make me feel better in the long run. I wanna feel better, I really do. Because stress is no joke. And then, on the 21st of May, my cousin died and, um...56 years old and he’s gone now. I know he was dealing with CHF so...life is short.” -Kris D.</i>
<ol start="8">
 	<li>What were some challenges you faced with this project? With taking your BP?</li>
</ol>
<i>“Getting the routine of getting it started and doing it every day” -Sharon E.</i>
<ol start="9">
 	<li>What were some successes?</li>
</ol>
<i>“Well, the biggest success is getting my BP under control to where I know the things that I ought to do and I know the things I should not do as far as the things I shouldn’t eat or how much of the things I shouldn’t eat. I should implement more fruits and vegetables, less fried foods, more baked foods or grilled foods. And cut out a lot of the pork and beef. And...I might hate myself for saying it...and the sweets. Every once in awhile brother, every once in awhile.” -Jarvis J.</i>

<i>“Having someone as an advocate for your health.” -Sharon E.</i>
<ol start="10">
 	<li>What’s the most important thing you’ve learned during our time together? What are your takeaways?</li>
</ol>
<i>“It’s, man, I’m thankful for...really, really [helped] me. From the starting, you know, I’m kind of, man, I was busy. Make a lot of money doing my job. See, now I know, money is nothing. Take care of myself and my family...you know, that’s the first priority. My kids, we used to have soda all the time in this house. They can drink soda once a while but I tell them, don’t bring any soda. You guys have to drink water.” -Toutai H.</i>
<ol start="11">
 	<li>What would you like your provider to know about this project?</li>
</ol>
<i>“That it will save lives. It will save people from having aneurysms, strokes, heart attacks. All they have to do is give the program a chance to work for them and once they give the program a chance to work for them, they will see the changes in their lives.” -Jarvis J.</i>

<i>“That it needs to continue. More people need to be made aware and have the advantage of being involved in it.” -Susan B.</i>

<i>“That this project should continue, if possible. If not by you, someone else come in. I think it should continue because it’s very important, like I said, for the patient to have that 1-on-1 with someone else besides the physician. Because sometimes when you go to your physician’s appointment, you’re basically being rushed and they’re not, you know, really listening or really concerned.” -Kris D.</i>

<i>“It’s a good program. They need to keep it. It helps to have someone come in and teach you things you don’t know nothing about like exercising, how to eat, how to stretch, how to breathe.” -Linda H.</i>

<i>“Most of us are seniors, and they have to have motivation to do something. And your visits and talking and stuff like that gives them company and helps motivate them.” -Sharon E.</i>
<ol start="12">
 	<li>Will you continue to do the things you’ve learned from this project?</li>
</ol>
<i>“Yes I will. Even after you guys are gone and the next group of young people come in, I will be a part of it.” -Jarvis J.</i>

<i>“Yes, absolutely. Including taking my blood pressure” -Susan B.</i>
<p style="padding-left:30px"></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>891</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-10-28 10:00:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-10-28 10:00:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:07:41]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:07:41]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[lets-take-a-deep-breath-managing-hypertension-by-bridging-the-clinic-home-healthcare-gap]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blood-pressure"><![CDATA[blood pressure]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="california"><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="health"><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="health-and-medicine"><![CDATA[Health and Medicine]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="hypertension"><![CDATA[hypertension]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="medical"><![CDATA[medical]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="medicine"><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="project"><![CDATA[project]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[913]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[timeline_notification]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1477674625]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[28331989399]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[913]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[timeline_notification]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1477674625]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[28331989399]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[913]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[913]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[timeline_notification]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1477674625]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[timeline_notification]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1477674625]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[28331989399]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[28331989399]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1553138866;s:7:"payload";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1149]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>26</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Kamal]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[skamal@ucdavis.edu]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[73.41.23.223]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-10-28 11:32:50]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-10-28 18:32:50]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Fantastic project! I really enjoyed reading about it.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[comment]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
						<wp:commentmeta>
	<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1477723922.4141590595245361328125;s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:11:"ndstrossman";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
						<wp:commentmeta>
	<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[email_notification_notqueued]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1477723921]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
						<wp:commentmeta>
	<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[jabber_published]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1477723921]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
						<wp:commentmeta>
	<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1477679571.412355899810791015625;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
						<wp:commentmeta>
	<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
						<wp:commentmeta>
	<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1477683618.4923279285430908203125;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
							</wp:comment>
					</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[1401-heart-health-art]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/lets-take-a-deep-breath-managing-hypertension-by-bridging-the-clinic-home-healthcare-gap/1401-heart-health-art/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 07:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sburgess]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2016/10/1401-heart-health-art.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>913</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-10-28 00:25:08]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-10-28 07:25:08]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2016-10-28 00:25:08]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2016-10-28 07:25:08]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[1401-heart-health-art]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>891</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2016/10/1401-heart-health-art.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2016/10/1401-heart-health-art.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:600;s:6:"height";i:479;s:4:"file";s:33:"2016/10/1401-heart-health-art.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:3:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"1401-heart-health-art-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"1401-heart-health-art-300x240.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:240;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"1401-heart-health-art-600x372.jpg";s:5:"width";i:600;s:6:"height";i:372;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:2:"23";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:48:"Leaf Aptus-II 8(LI302624   )/Mamiya 645DF/645AFD";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:10:"1381881600";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:2:"80";s:3:"iso";s:2:"80";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:6:"0.0025";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"1";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[UC Davis Hosts DataRescue Event To Archive Climate Research]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/uc-davis-hosts-datarescue-event-to-archive-climate-research/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.wordpress.com/?p=1035</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[By N. J. Griffen, English, ‘17

<strong>Author’s Note:</strong>

<span style="font-weight:400">“I chose to write about this topic as a response to one of the many uncertainties that exists under our newly elected president, Donald Trump. More specifically, this article is meant to encompass the nationwide effort by scientists, professors, researchers and archivists to safeguard, backup and protect work conducted in the realm of climate science. This topic, I believe, should be integrally important to most residents of this planet; due to the fact that we have no choice but to live the entirety of our lives here on earth. Therefore, my interview of the archivists at UC Davis seeks to uncover the motives and connotations that the DataRescue Davis event assumes.”</span>

<!--more-->

<span style="font-weight:400">In a time where the availability of information seems to be infinite, it can often be forgotten that as easy as it is to publish scientific data on the internet, it is just as easy if not easier to delete it. So, the</span> <span style="font-weight:400">scientific community felt obligated to respond to this vulnerability. As a result, this gave birth to the DataRefuge project.</span>

<span style="font-weight:400">The DataRefuge project began at the University of Pennsylvania with the primary goal being to spearhead the “</span><span style="font-weight:400">...</span><span style="font-weight:400"> identifying, assessing, prioritizing, securing, and distributing reliable copies of federal climate and environmental data so that it remains available to researchers." Due to the immense amount of climate and environmental research that happens at UC Davis, researchers felt the need to get involved. </span>

An ample amount of support was shown towards this idea, and so a formal event was planned. Publicized on Facebook by the UC Davis Library, the DataRescue Davis event welcomed all who desired to help in the process of preserving scientific research.

The DataRescue Davis event was held on Feb. 2, aiming to backup environmental and climate science data sets in partnership with the DataRefuge project’s archival system. Although archiving data of this sort had largely begun in 2008 during the Obama Administration, the Trump administration has incited a newfound urgency. This comes in turn with Trump’s recent order for the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to purge their website of all climate change information.

<span style="font-weight:400">By speaking with Kevin Miller, University Archivist, and Vessela Ensberg, Associate Director of the Data Management Program, the specificities of the DataRescue Davis event were made clear. </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">“The event here itself was on the third floor of the library in the data science initiative space,” Miller said. Furthermore, he emphasized the fact that they were at full capacity for the event with a mix of both undergraduate and graduate participants. Most pleasantly surprising, expressed the pair, was that they ended up hosting a majority of technically sound website crawlers. This allowed them to give proper attention to novice participants, while also being able to keep productivity up.  </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">Since this project is by nature political and set within an academic atmosphere, the archivists allowed its participants to remain anonymous as long as they had a desire to contribute. “We didn’t necessarily know a lot about the people who showed up, because we wanted to keep open the option of anonymity,” Miller said. “We wanted to keep it a safe space, but we had a sense that the majority of them had a UC Davis connection.” </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">Both Ensberg and Miller reiterated that the archiving of data will always be important -- “the more copies, the better” is their agreed upon philosophy. By virtue of this, Miller said that their jobs are agnostic of political attachments. Yet, Miller did not think that the DataRefuge project as a whole was absent of an opinion. </span>

“In terms of DataRefuge, I think that it is a direct response to the federal administration,” Miller said. The DataRefuge project uses servers over the northern border in Canada, which as an action standing on its own implies thorough suspicion towards the Trump administration’s agenda.

“I think there was some fear that climate and environmental data was particularly susceptible to being suppressed,” Miller said. “Because of shifting priorities in the administration, there may be less money going to support access to this material.”

The event proved to be successful, both Ensberg and Miller are continuing to organize the data sets acquired. “There was a lot of enthusiasm, so we don’t rule out another event,” Ensberg stated. “But we’re still finishing up work from the past event.”

In the following weeks, there will be a slew of likeminded DataRescue events being held throughout the country.

<span style="font-weight:400">All future and past DataRescue events can be seen </span><a href="http://www.ppehlab.org/datarescue-events"><span style="font-weight:400">here.</span></a>

Sources:
<ol>
 	<li style="font-weight:400"><span style="font-weight:400">“About DataRefuge.” DataRefuge.org. 27 Feb. 2017. Web. (</span><a href="https://www.datarefuge.org/about"><span style="font-weight:400">https://www.datarefuge.org/about</span></a><span style="font-weight:400">)</span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight:400"><span style="font-weight:400">“Donald Trump orders Environmental Protection Agency to delete all climate change information from its website.”</span><a href="http://independent.co.uk"> <span style="font-weight:400">independent.co.uk</span></a><span style="font-weight:400">. 25 Jan. 2017. Web. (</span><a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/donald-trump-environmental-protection-agency-website-climate-change-global-warming-a7544621.html"><span style="font-weight:400">http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/donald-trump-environmental-protection-agency-website-climate-change-global-warming-a7544621.html</span></a><span style="font-weight:400">)</span></li>
</ol>
<span style="font-weight:400">Edited by: Connie Chen, Chantele Karim, and Nicole Strossman</span>

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1035</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-03-14 10:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-03-14 10:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:06:33]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:06:33]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[uc-davis-hosts-datarescue-event-to-archive-climate-research]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="climate-change"><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="environment-2"><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="environment"><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="interview"><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1040]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2866898021]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1040]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2866898021]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1040]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2866898021]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1040]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2866898021]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1552969540;s:7:"payload";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1447]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[data_climate]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/uc-davis-hosts-datarescue-event-to-archive-climate-research/data_climate/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 02:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sburgess]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2017/03/data_climate.png</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1040</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-03-13 19:39:28]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-03-14 02:39:28]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2017-03-13 19:39:28]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2017-03-14 02:39:28]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[data_climate]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1035</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2017/03/data_climate.png]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2017/03/data_climate.png]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:2136;s:6:"height";i:1424;s:4:"file";s:24:"2017/03/data_climate.png";s:5:"sizes";a:6:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"data_climate-150x150.png";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"data_climate-300x200.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:200;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"data_climate-768x512.png";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:512;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:25:"data_climate-1024x683.png";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:683;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"data_climate-672x372.png";s:5:"width";i:672;s:6:"height";i:372;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:25:"twentyfourteen-full-width";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:25:"data_climate-1038x576.png";s:5:"width";i:1038;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Aggie Transcript Interview—Dr. Daniel Starr]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/interview-with-professor-dan-starr/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.wordpress.com/?p=1049</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[By Lauren Uchiyama, Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, ’17
<p style="padding-left:30px"><strong>Author’s Note: </strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px"><span style="font-weight:400">"I chose to write this piece because I felt Dr. Dan Starr is unique in that he is equally passionate about  teaching and research.  As an undergraduate in his BIS 104 cell biology class, I feel he highlights research well by teaching us from an experimental and historical perspective, which makes learning even more fun and interesting.  His reputation as a difficult, yet acclaimed educator has made him one of the most prominent biology professors at UC Davis.  I hope you enjoy getting to know him as much as I did!"</span></p>
<!--more-->

<span style="font-weight:400">Dr. Daniel Starr is a professor and Director of the Biochemistry, Molecular, Cellular and Developmental Biology (BMCDB) Graduate Group at the University of California, Davis. For the past 14 years here, he has made crucial discoveries on nuclei movement and positioning, studying nuclear envelope KASH and SUN proteins. Though this concept has profound impacts on muscular dystrophy, neuronal development, and cancer, little is known about how these proteins are regulated.  In his most recent </span><i><span style="font-weight:400">Development</span></i><span style="font-weight:400"> publication, Dr. Starr and his students established an in vivo model to help understand nuclei movement through constricted spaces (1).   </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">In addition to research, Dr. Starr has also established the undergraduate cell biology course, BIS104. He even went on sabbatical to write our online textbook, “Cellular Biology. Experimental Approaches to Cellular Processes and Molecular Medicine.” This textbook contains homework, quizzes and chapter flashcards to ensure students’ understanding of cell biology from an experimental perspective. </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">I sat down with Dr. Starr to gain insight on his background, career, and interests both in and out of the lab. His passion for academia and family rang clear, and I think everyone can learn a thing or two from him. I know I have.  </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: Where did you do your training? </i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS:</span> <span style="font-weight:400"> I grew up in Minneapolis, and went to a small liberal arts school in Maine, called Colby College. Between my junior and senior year, I got an internship at the University of Iowa and worked in a microbiology lab for two months.  That's where I learned research is really fun.  I graduated with my PhD from Cornell University where I studied kinetochore proteins and how chromosomes segregate during mitosis. Then as a postdoctoral fellow at the University of Colorado, Boulder I started the work I’m doing right now. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: What made you want to pursue research?</i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS: </span> <span style="font-weight:400">I was always encouraged to pursue different things.  In hindsight, I’m lucky that it worked out because I went to grad school and I loved it. But, at the time, I had no idea what I was getting into.  Part of it was also when I was graduating in the early 90s, the economy was on a downturn and there weren’t a ton of opportunities but grad school was like, we’ll pay you! I’m like, sign me up, where do I go?  </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: What is your favorite part about this career?</i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS: </span> <span style="font-weight:400">This career is many jobs, but is primarily research and teaching. There aren’t many jobs where you can do two different things that feed off of one another. To be able to do two things I love is really lucky.  </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">Even though I only teach BIS104 Winter Quarter, I teach grad students and undergraduates in lab every day, a graduate course for a few weeks, and work on this textbook.  My major teaching responsibility is BIS104, but there is all the informal education you do on a campus as well.  I’m very proud that the students flock to me in BIS104, and I’m also proud that if you go to ratemyprofessor.com, they think I’m hard. Right? So I’m proud that they think I’m hard and yet still come. So to me, that's about as good as it gets. </span>

<span style="font-weight:400">Then at [Colby College], we had real life interactions with people not from our generation, and that's one of the things I love about being on a college campus. I’m interacting with people daily who aren’t in my generation, and I think it’s really important to keep talking with people who are at different stages in their life. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: What is your least favorite part about this job?</i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS:</span> <span style="font-weight:400">There’s a lot of frustration at the slow speed things change at high education, and how hard it is to create change. It’s difficult to push education in the right direction and I tend to spend more time than I should on these things. I get frustrated there are 280 students in my BIS104 class, and I get one TA — that isn’t the way we should be educating the best kids in California. As a taxpayer, there should be smaller classes with more attention so we don't have to take stupid multiple choice tests. I alone can’t change the course to a class of 75 students. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: For what it’s worth, I think BIS104 is structured really well. </i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS: </span> <span style="font-weight:400">Yeah, but I’ve had to work really hard on that.</span>

<b><i>LU: I mean, you wrote a whole textbook. </i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS:</span> <span style="font-weight:400">Right, so this is a product I’ve been working on for 13 years. I’m doing the best I can with the resources I have to try and deliver you guys the best product because you are the future of California. I do really love teaching BIS104, I just wish I was teaching 50 students with small discussion sections, similar to my journal club. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: With all these responsibilities here, how do you balance work and family life? </i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS:</span> <span style="font-weight:400">Part of it is you have to focus and be efficient when you are at work. I put family first but that doesn't mean work is non-existent. I try to limit my trips and build boundaries and limits; this job could take up 90 hours a week if I let it, but I stop it after a reasonable amount of time.  This morning, my daughter was presenting at an oral language fair and I just made the decision to come in late because I wanted to hear my daughter give this talk.</span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: What is something that most people don’t know about you? </i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS:</span> <span style="font-weight:400">Well, so in work life balance, there are no hobbies because that's part of the balance.  Hobbies went out the window when I had kids. And after work and life, there’s family and there’s not much other stuff. I have hobbies that aren’t very exciting like golfing, skiing and camping, but I don't get to do those as much as I want to. I like to read novels. The life of a professor is not usually too exciting outside of being a professor.  </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: Because that is your passion.  </i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS:</span> <span style="font-weight:400">Exactly. I mean, my hobby is thinking about science. I don't think most people realize I wrote the [BIS104] textbook. I didn't have to do this as part of the job, but I’m really glad I did. It was a great experience and the students seem to respond to it quite well, so it’s been fun. I’ve been trying to get it adopted outside of UC Davis because I want my voice to be heard, and I have a list of topics I’d like to add to the book. It was really important for me to include all the experimental design elements to get students thinking. The students in labs think that way, but the other ones don't, so I like talking about things from a historical perspective. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>LU: What advice do you have for students as they continue their education here at UC Davis?</i></b>

<span style="font-weight:400">DS: </span> <span style="font-weight:400">The biggest thing you need to take advantage of is you need to get into a lab and do research. And it doesn't matter what the research is on, but this is a major, tier one research institution. I get merits and promotions primarily based on my research, not my teaching. That's what you can’t do at a CSU or a small liberal arts school. But at UC Davis, there’s this amazing research in all these fields and if you’re not taking advantage of it, you are missing out. The education you get in the lab is way better than you can get in any class.  </span>

Sources
<ol>
 	<li style="font-weight:400"><span style="font-weight:400">Bone, C.R., Chang, Y.T., Cain, N.E., Murphy, S.P. and Starr, D.A. </span><span style="font-weight:400">Nuclei migrate through constricted spaces using microtubule motors and actin networks in </span><i><span style="font-weight:400">C. elegans</span></i><span style="font-weight:400"> hypodermal cells (2016). </span><b>Development</b> <i><span style="font-weight:400">143</span></i><span style="font-weight:400">, 4193-4202; </span><a href="http://dev.biologists.org/content/143/22/4193"><span style="font-weight:400">http://dev.biologists.org/content/143/22/4193</span></a></li>
</ol>
<i><span style="font-weight:400">This interview has been lightly edited for clarity and brevity. </span></i>

<span style="font-weight:400">Edited by Bukre Coskun, Wren Greaney, &amp; Carly Cheung</span>

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1049</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-03-24 13:38:29]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-03-24 13:38:29]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:05:46]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:05:46]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[interview-with-professor-dan-starr]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="cell-biology"><![CDATA[cell biology]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="interview"><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1052]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3237672485]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1052]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3237672485]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1052]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3237672485]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1052]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3237672485]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[geo_public]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1554283914;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:2005;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:1984;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:1921;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1497]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[How_proteins_are_made_NSF]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/interview-with-professor-dan-starr/how_proteins_are_made_nsf/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 20:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sburgess]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2017/03/how_proteins_are_made_nsf.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1052</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-03-24 13:38:04]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-03-24 20:38:04]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2017-03-24 13:38:04]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2017-03-24 20:38:04]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how_proteins_are_made_nsf]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1049</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2017/03/how_proteins_are_made_nsf.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2017/03/how_proteins_are_made_nsf.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:3783;s:6:"height";i:1958;s:4:"file";s:37:"2017/03/how_proteins_are_made_nsf.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:6:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:37:"how_proteins_are_made_nsf-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:37:"how_proteins_are_made_nsf-300x155.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:155;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:37:"how_proteins_are_made_nsf-768x398.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:398;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"how_proteins_are_made_nsf-1024x530.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:530;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:37:"how_proteins_are_made_nsf-672x372.jpg";s:5:"width";i:672;s:6:"height";i:372;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"twentyfourteen-full-width";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"how_proteins_are_made_nsf-1038x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1038;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"1";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Aggie Transcript Interview—Dr. Walter Leal]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/aggie-transcript-interview-dr-walter-leal/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.wordpress.com/?p=1058</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400">By Bukre Coskun, Cell Biology, ‘18</span>

<b>Author’s Note:</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400">“As a student in Professor Walter Leal’s biochemistry class, I was inspired by his dedication to motivating students and obvious enthusiasm for his field of research. Professor Walter Leal has achieved international recognition for his research on the molecular basis of insect communication and insect olfaction. Leal, a professor in the UC Davis Department of Molecular and Cellular Biology and former chair of the UC Davis Department of Entomology, has made significant strides towards understanding how chemicals deter mosquitos. He has identified key mosquito receptors that can guide the development of better mosquito repellents to prevent the spread of deadly diseases. He is a past president of the International Society of Chemical Ecology, an elected fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), and the first non-Japanese scientist to earn tenure in the Japan Ministry of Agriculture. I had a conversation with Professor Leal about his path to research, his philosophy on teaching, and the significance of his work with insects.” </span>

<!--more-->

<b><i>BC: Did you have a moment where you thought, “This is the subject I want to study?”</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">When I went to college, I was not sure what I wanted to do, to be honest. Initially, I wanted to do electronic engineering, which was a mistake! So, I changed my mind and did some chemical engineering. I got my first degree in chemical engineering, but did not enjoy my interaction with industry. For my PhD, I changed my route to pesticide chemistry and then to biochemistry. . . . It’s ok if you don’t know what you want to do, it’s very normal. Once you get in, you find out what it’s like. Some people look at a parent as a model, but most people don’t have much information about the field and if it’s what they want to do for the rest of their lives. So, they keep changing. I changed and I’m very happy that I changed. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC:You invest a lot of time preparing videos and providing office hours for your biochemistry students. What’s your teaching philosophy?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">First of all, I want to motivate students. I try to sit in the place of the students. Whenever I prepare lectures, I think, “. . . If I was in the place of the students, would I be able to understand this explanation?” So, my philosophy is that I have to motivate the students and they have to continue the work by themselves. If they are not interested in the subject, they will just invest time to pass the exam. Motivation, I think, is the most important thing. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: Is that also why you do the Skype interviews with people from industry?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">Yes, because I think that the textbook can be boring since it doesn’t have much new information. So much happens in life in every aspect of science that we study. Skype interviews are a way to tell people, “You see, what I said here is not just textbook, it’s real life, it’s going on in the industry.” For example, we are going to study purification of proteins and the industry is doing this every single day. They are making new proteins for medicine and if you bring some of these examples to class, the students will realize this thing is not only for the exam. . . . </span><span style="font-weight: 400">That’s why I invited Renner Burkle from Genentech. His examples from the Vacaville plant were right on target. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: You do research with insects. Most people see insects as pests. What sparked your interest in them?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">I started with an emphasis on agricultural pests. When I studied pesticide chemistry...I started to use environmentally friendly strategies to control insects. In other words, I identified chemicals and pheromones that insects use in communication that can be a tool to interrupt that communication. When I moved to Davis, there was this West Nile Virus that came into California, so I thought I would. . . emphasize a bit more on insects of medical entomology, like mosquitos. There are a number of diseases mosquitoes carry. There is malaria, dengue, West Nile Virus and now Zika. I thought focusing on medical entomology would be very useful for society. . . . We have been working on repellants and attractants and many other things with mosquitos. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: You do research on the olfactory receptors of mosquitos. Can you talk a bit about the life cycle of mosquitos and how they utilize smell in this life cycle?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">The female needs blood to provide the nutrition for what will become the larva of mosquitoes. Mosquitos use a combination of many things to tune in on the host. They have senses for temperature, for humidity, for carbon dioxide and for chemicals that are coming out from our skin. The biology of mosquitoes is such that they are in the environment and they try to find a mate. . . . in mosquitos and most insects, the female keeps the sperm for later. In the case of mosquitos, she holds this sperm and goes to find the blood meal she needs to fertilize her eggs. Once the eggs have become very rich in nutrition, they come down from the oviduct into the water and are fertilized one by one with the sperm that she accumulated. It’s amazing biology! </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">The problem is that she might infect someone with a virus or pathogen that causes some disease when she goes for her blood meal. That’s not her “intention,” she just wants to try to get a meal. But let’s say that she bites you and you are infected with the Zika Virus. The female does not lay eggs only once, she has what we call multiple gonotrophic cycles. . . . She might mate a second time. She needs another blood meal, so if she had a virus that replicated in her body, she becomes the bridge in between people. That’s how you transmit a virus. . . . That leads to another type of research that we do with repellants. We want to find how these repellants work and what kinds of repellents we can make that are better for people to use. People don’t like some of the repellents because it smells bad and things like that. So, we are looking into this.  </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: With the study of repellants, what kind of behavioral assays do you do with the mosquitos?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">We don’t want people to put their hand inside of the cage. . . . we do some research with mosquitos that are infected so it would be immoral, at least unethical, to put someone there! Also, a human hand is not reproducible. One day we may attract mosquitos and one day we may not. That’s when the biochemical engineer in me came to help. I was able to develop a device that mimics the human hand and attracts mosquitos. . . . On one side we put this artificial hand and on the other side we put this artificial hand plus some chemicals that we know might be a repellant. Then we compare the response of the mosquito to one side or the other. This way, we can assess whether a certain chemical is a repellant and knock down receptors using technology that is available. . . . </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: Do you collaborate with other labs?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">These days no one can do science on their own. I do all my work with infected mosquitoes in Brazil. . . . Last year, I went maybe four or five times for my research on the Zika Virus. I could get permission from UC Davis to get mosquitoes and infect them here, but it’s a more realistic situation when you have the virus that is circulating in the mosquitos in the moment. . . . In Davis, for example, I would get a virus from Puerto Rico or Africa and I would have mosquitos from Davis, but they’ve never seen each other! It’s not the real answer for the question. There are lots of surprises in science. We think, “Ah, that’s fine, we can use that mosquito from Davis and a virus from Africa,” but they have never seen each other. They probably won’t react the same way. So, collaboration is very important and we have to keep the doors open. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: You also have a study with moths and the pheromones they use in mating. It’s chemically very complicated. What are some challenges you face?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">It depends on the moth. We have done work on the receptor side but I have also done lots of research on identifying those compounds. Sometimes these compounds are very complex and the major challenge is that insects use very minute amounts. If the amounts were very large, any chemist would be able to identify those compounds. . . . we have to use some resources and techniques that allow us to guess those structures without seeing anything. Some well qualified scientists spend twenty years trying to find these compounds and they never do! In a couple of years, we were able to break down these structures. Sometimes persistence and luck is what you need.  </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: Speaking of structures of compounds, you found that the repellant DEET has a structure that is similar to a chemical that plants give off to defend themselves. How often do you see evolutionary connections like this?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">The question of DEET is not entirely resolved but. . . we found the exact receptor for DEET. DEET is not a natural compound, so we wanted to know why it repels mosquitos and the foundation for this. We made the connection that mosquitos also go to plants for a bit of nectar to have energy for flight. . . . We decided to take a look at the structures of a plant compound. We found that the receptors for DEET also respond to a compound plants use to repel enemies. But there is still a lot more to find out. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Questions of evolution are complicated because it’s all hypotheses and we test these hypotheses. A good way to find a solid answer is if we find different kinds of mosquitoes with the same pathway. All these mosquitos come from an ancestral species that separate at some point but we have a good answer for just one group. We don’t know if our findings are applicable to malaria mosquitoes, for example. So, we still have a little bit more work to do. The good thing about science is that the answer is never over. . . . We are never satisfied, there is never an end, there is always a little more. . . . </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: Where do you hope you research will take you five years down the road. Where do you hope to be?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">My goodness, that’s a very difficult question! I have no idea what we are going to be doing five years from now. Every day in the lab we discover something new. If we discover something new and it takes us in a completely different direction, we are going to follow that direction. . . . For example, as we look at those receptors and we find something there that is maybe different in known biology, I want to go deep into that question. </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: Who, scientists or otherwise, have inspired you in your life?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">There are so many people. A famous professor in chemical ecology at Cornell [Jerrold Meinwald] is one of the people that inspired me. He is 90 years old. . . I spent some time in his lab many years ago, he is a very inspirational person. There are lots of people but I don’t want to say names because I might forget someone. He is just one of the people whose line of thought I follow but we do completely different research now. He does more organic chemistry and I’m doing more molecular work. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">If you ask me about a teacher, I would say that the person who influenced my teaching philosophy the most was my high school chemistry teacher [</span><span style="font-weight: 400">Aloisio Sotero]. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">. . . He was a very vibrant teacher and liked to motivate students and get everyone engaged. I probably got a lot of influence from that. My second year [of college], he quit his teaching job. Brazil didn’t have a lot science teachers so they got permission for high schools to hire university students. The high school hired me as his replacement. I was in college and I was teaching high school for a number of years. Maybe 75% or more of my Facebook friends are my high school students from when I was teaching them. I was very young and almost the same age as these students. . . . </span>

&nbsp;

<b><i>BC: What is one piece of advice you would give to young researchers?</i></b>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">WL:</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">Tomorrow I will have the Nobel laureate Jules Hoffmann answer exactly that question in class! Why don’t you take his advice from tomorrow’s lecture? He is one of the few people that got the Nobel prize for things related to insect in recent years.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Author’s Note: Jules Hoffmann advised us to find a good topic of research not yet covered by too many other people. He told us to work hard and remain connected with art and literature. He warned us that it’s not a good idea to dedicate your life to just one thing; variety is the key to success. </span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">Editor’s Note: This conversation has been lightly edited for clarity and brevity. </span></i>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">Edited by Lauren Uchiyama &amp; Lo Tuan</span>

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1058</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-04-07 11:28:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-04-07 11:28:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:04:03]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:04:03]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[aggie-transcript-interview-dr-walter-leal]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="entymology"><![CDATA[entymology]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="interview"><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="uc-davis"><![CDATA[uc davis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1060]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3748452777]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1060]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3748452777]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1060]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3748452777]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_published]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_rest_api_client_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1060]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_job_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3748452777]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1553439827;s:7:"payload";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1172]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[mosquito-83639_960_720]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/aggie-transcript-interview-dr-walter-leal/mosquito-83639_960_720/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 18:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sburgess]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2017/04/mosquito-83639_960_720.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1060</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-04-07 11:28:11]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-04-07 18:28:11]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2017-04-07 11:28:11]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2017-04-07 18:28:11]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[mosquito-83639_960_720]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1058</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2017/04/mosquito-83639_960_720.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2017/04/mosquito-83639_960_720.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:960;s:6:"height";i:586;s:4:"file";s:34:"2017/04/mosquito-83639_960_720.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"mosquito-83639_960_720-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"mosquito-83639_960_720-300x183.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:183;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"mosquito-83639_960_720-768x469.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:469;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"mosquito-83639_960_720-672x372.jpg";s:5:"width";i:672;s:6:"height";i:372;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"twentyfourteen-full-width";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"mosquito-83639_960_720-960x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:960;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[A Conversation with Dr. Kate Scow: “I just totally lost my heart to soil”]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/a-conversation-with-dr-kate-scow-i-just-totally-lost-my-heart-to-soil/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 03:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/?p=1578</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400">By Sara Ludwick, Environmental Science and Management, 2019</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Author’s note: I read about Dr. Scow’s research while looking for a faculty member to interview for a class assignment. She is a professor of Soil Science and Microbial Ecology at UC Davis, and her research emphasizes microorganisms’ roles in providing ecosystems services. Dr. Scow was featured in an article on a UC Davis website about carbon sequestration as a tactic to address climate change, and from there I discovered Russell Ranch, where she serves as Director (1). I immediately became interested in the variety of experiments conducted on the experimental farm, and began to learn more about Dr. Scow’s work. Her work is extensive; in addition to directing Russell Ranch, she actively works with Ugandan smallholder farms on irrigation. I sat down with Dr. Scow to discuss her passion for soil, what her research has taught her, how her relationship with soil has evolved, and what other people can learn from the powerful ecosystem that lives underground. </span><!--more-->

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">SL:</span></i> <i><span style="font-weight: 400">What sparked your interest in soils?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KS: When I was fourteen my family drove across Europe through a number of countries. For some reason, I collected a soil sample from each country. I have no idea why I did that, except [to have it] as a memory of a place, a different kind of memory than sugar packets and postcards...And I didn't think a</span><span style="font-weight: 400">bout soil ag</span><span style="font-weight: 400">ain for years. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Then in college I studied</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> biology. I was really interested in animal behavior...I finished my Bachelor's Degree at Antioch College and then went to University of Chicago and studied Evolutionary Biology. I worked at Brookfield Zoo </span><span style="font-weight: 400">near Chicago</span><span style="font-weight: 400">, and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">did research on social behavior of baboons and big cats</span><span style="font-weight: 400">...I ended up leaving graduate school and moving to Boston. I worked for an environmental consulting firm...and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">the remarkable thing I discovered there was soil. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">I learned that soil was so important yet remarkably invisible to most, a combination of being so significant yet so overlooked. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">I think that really pulled me towards it. Soil is at the center of so much of what is happening globally--the flow of energy, the cycling of elements, and it is the home of enormous biodiversity. We didn’t even know how diverse soil was back then, [but it was] so important and so mysterious and there was so much more to learn. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">And I always use the word “love” when I talk about soil. I fell in love and just totally lost my heart to soil. </span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">SL: How has your interest in soil science evolved since then?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KS: </span><span style="font-weight: 400">I began my career working on contamination by organic pollutants and their biodegradation by microorganisms in soil. I'm really interested in the capacity of indigenous microbial communities to break down contaminants in the environment. From there I branched out to studying the roles of soil microorganisms in agricultural systems...I became interested in soil processes and microbial communities on the farm, and their connections to human communities and the larger food system.</span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">SL: Can you briefly explain the purpose of Russell Ranch and how you got involved as Director?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">K</span><span style="font-weight: 400">S: Russell Ranch Sustainable Agriculture Facility, part of the Agricultural Sustainability Institute, is one of [a few] long term research experiments on the planet, initially founded almost thirty years ago. I became Director about 10 years ago. The goal is to study the effects of different agricultural practices and management systems on the environmental and economic sustainability, and resilience, of agroecosystems. Russell Ranch is a hub for researchers and stakeholders to come together, collaborate and exchange ideas on a common experiment.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">The [other main purpose] is long term research. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Most research projects last two or three years if you’re lucky. If you are studying sustainability, change is often small and incremental, over long periods of time. You won’t see much in just a couple of years. Longer time is needed to detect changes, good or bad, and relate them back to effects of different practices: fertilizer use, irrigation practices, soil management, or to phenomena you can’t control like climate change.</span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">SL: In your time as director, what have been some of your favorite findings?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KS: There’s a number of interesting things. We have compared crop yields and soil quality of organic and conventional tomato-corn rotations in our Century Experiment after 20 years. The conventional system receives synthetic fertilizers and synthetic pesticides; the organic is fertilized by winter cover crops and composted poultry manure. Averaged over the years, the yields of conventional and organic tomatoes are approximately the same. But what is different and quite dramatic is that conventional yields vary a lot, year to year, sometimes higher and sometimes lower. In contrast, the yields of the organic system are far more stable and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">seem</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> more resilient to changes in weather, pests or whatever is underlying those variations. Soils are really different too! The organic soils have about 30% more carbon and microbial biomass, higher aggregate structure and water infiltration rates than the conventional soils. We are sequencing their microbiomes now and anticipate some major differences!</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">A food chemist, Alyson Mitchell, [is] interested in antioxidants in food [and] measured the flavonoid content of tomato fruit in organic and conventional management systems. In our archived tomato samples collected over more than a decade, she found significantly higher flavonoids in organic than conventional tomatoes appearing after 4-5 years of management. This kind of research on how agricultural practices affect the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">quality</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> and not just </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">quantity</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> of food is so important these days with our focus on nutrition. Russell Ranch is an excellent place to study these questions.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Research we’ve done on deficit irrigation of tomatoes has revealed that we can reduce water inputs to tomatoes to as much as 40% of what we’d predict based on the plant’s evapotranspiration (ET). We start the reduction 6 weeks before harvest. Not only are the tomato yields the same as if you’d given them 100% water, but the solids content of the fruit is much higher. The tomato processors like this because it reduces the amount of water they need to get rid of. It is definitely one of those win-win results.</span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">SL: Generally, how has looking deep into the ground below shaped the way you view the rest of the world?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KS: I get a lot of inspiration from the soil...it’s anchored me, I suppose. I'm really interested in this question: is soil alive, or is soil a habitat for living things? I think our relationship t</span><span style="font-weight: 400">o soil</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> would be different if we viewed it as a livi</span><span style="font-weight: 400">ng thing. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Of course some folks have had that concept forever; living soil is interwoven in the idea of Pachamama in the Andes. In the US, in a lot of modern agricultural practices, soil is treated more as an inert medium.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">I sometimes say soil is everywhere but it's nowhere. Though we walk on it everyday, many don’t think twice and know little about this tremendous life force that’s going on beneath our feet. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">With climate change and soil erosion, it is more pressing than ever for all of us to learn how to take better care of soils and strengthen our relationship with it. This is the first time I’ve seen so much attention on soil from the public. I’m very curious to see where this new attention goes in terms of widespread adoption of regenerative agricultural practices and policies that protect the soil.</span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">SL: You were saying</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400"> it isn’t very obvious what's ha</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400">ppening to the soil. </span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KS: Soil is a bit secre</span><span style="font-weight: 400">tive and hard to read. I was one of the main science advisors for the film, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">The </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Symphony o</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400">f the Soil</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">. The director Deborah Garcia tells the story about when she first started filming, she stood in a beautiful field on a farm and said “OK shoot” [to her cameraman] and he said “I don't see anything.” The film went on to reveal how much actually is going on in soil. You just don’t see much with your bare eyes.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Soil is in trouble. We are losing it globally at alarming rates--through erosion and pollution and urban development--and it takes an enormous amount of time to rebuild soil. As a society we are far more aware of the impacts of degraded water and air than soil. Soil needs champions. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Fortunately, awareness around soil is growing…for example, the concept that soil needs to be healthy to provide healthy food and in turn healthy humans [is becoming more publicized]. More farmers are adopting practices to regenerate soils. California and US agencies are developing policies to promote soil health. And I’ve noticed a growing interest in the public and among students. Though we have far to go, I am hopeful. </span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">This interview has been lightly edited for clarity and brevity.</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Sources</span>
<ol>
 	<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Kerlin, Kat. “A Climate Change Solution Below Our Feet.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Science and Climate, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">UC Davis, </span>15 May 2017, <a href="http://climatechange.ucdavis.edu/news/climate-change-solution-beneath-feet/">http://climatechange.ucdavis.edu/news/climate-change-solution-beneath-feet/</a></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1578</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-03-07 03:21:51]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-03-07 03:21:51]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:06:08]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2019-01-30 03:06:08]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[a-conversation-with-dr-kate-scow-i-just-totally-lost-my-heart-to-soil]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="environment"><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="interview"><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="soil"><![CDATA[soil]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1579]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1553936337;s:7:"payload";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2506]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[rucola-salad-plant-leaf]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/a-conversation-with-dr-kate-scow-i-just-totally-lost-my-heart-to-soil/rucola-salad-plant-leaf/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 03:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bgyoume]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2018/03/rucola-salad-plant-leaf.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1579</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-03-07 03:21:43]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-03-07 03:21:43]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2018-03-07 03:21:43]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2018-03-07 03:21:43]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rucola-salad-plant-leaf]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1578</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2018/03/rucola-salad-plant-leaf.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2018/03/rucola-salad-plant-leaf.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1125;s:6:"height";i:726;s:4:"file";s:35:"2018/03/rucola-salad-plant-leaf.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:10:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-300x194.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:194;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-768x496.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:496;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-1024x661.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:661;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-large-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-830x536.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:536;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"sydney-medium-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-small-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-230x148.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:148;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sydney-service-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-350x226.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:226;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:16:"sydney-mas-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-480x310.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:310;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"rucola-salad-plant-leaf-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"1";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Aggie Transcript Interview: Dr. Janine LaSalle]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/aggie-transcript-interview-dr-janine-lasalle/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 03:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rmhull]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/?p=1738</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[By Mari Hoffman, Genetics and Genomics ‘21

<span style="font-weight: 400">Author’s Note: I chose to interview Dr.LaSalle because of my interest in epigenetics and the relationship that our genes have with environmental interactions. Dr. LaSalle’s lab focuses on the role of epigenetics in the human autism-spectrum and many other neurodegenerative disorders. Her research group looks at the pathogenesis of the disorders by focusing on heritable changes that are not encoded in the DNA, such as DNA methylation and imprinted genes. It was an honor to get to talk to Dr. LaSalle about her research, as she is extremely passionate about this very complex and exciting topic.</span>

<!--more-->

<b>MH:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> What first got you interested in the research you do today?</span>

<b>JS: </b><span style="font-weight: 400">My lab studies epigenetics and gene environment interaction, a topic I find of great interest because genetics is never completely deterministic. I started out with my PhD in Immunology, and then in my post-doctoral fellowship, I studied epigenetics of imprinted disorders, which do not fit Mendelian genetics. More recently, my lab has gotten into sequencing technology, as we are interested in the interface of gene-environment interactions at the epigenetics level. With this, we can use the sequencing technology to predict who might get a disease in the future.</span>

<b>MH:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> You do research with genomic imprinting and DNA Methylation. Can you talk a bit about what that means and how it is used to understand how gene and environment interactions affect us?</span>

<b>JS:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> DNA methylation seems to be perceived as an off switch for genes, but the revised way of seeing it is as a mark of past transcription, which gives clues for future transcription. We know that genes are methylated at the earliest stages of life, specifically during embryonic development. Differences in methylation can indicate previous transcription activity. An example of this is autism, where most of the environmental factors occur </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">in utero.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> These changes cannot be sampled directly before birth. We can resort to sampling placenta or cord blood, which can give an idea of the changes that occurred before birth. I think of methylation as mining for clues, but it doesn't mean that we're going to find genes that are turned off by methylation.</span>

<b>MH:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> Do you find when looking at DNA methylation, evidence of environmental impact on methylation that is not encoded in the gene?</span>

<b>JS:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> That is our eventual goal. There are good examples of this, such as imprinted genes in oocytes or sperm. Oocytes may have certain transcripts that will be methylated on the maternal but not paternal chromosome, which is affected by the environment. The goal is to find other environmental exposures such as diet, etc. Folate is an important diet factor in methylation and can be found in prenatal vitamins, such as Vitamin B. Women are encouraged to take prenatal vitamins prior to pregnancy as it is protective for neural tube defects, autism, and schizophrenia.</span>

<b>MH:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> What creates the spectrum in Autism Spectrum Disorder?</span>

<b>JS:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400">Autism has a wide spectrum of diagnoses and a single gene only makes about 1 percent of cases. One of the disorders that we research is Rett Syndrome, a rare genetic form of autism. I find it interesting how there is a spectrum within the cognition and severity of symptoms. There is a range of disease severity ranging from someone who has high functioning Asperger's Syndrome, all the way down to someone who is nonverbal and may have an intellectual disability. This is where the gene environment interaction may come in. Genetically, you could say that one gene mutation is enough to cause autism, yet in a lot of cases the cause could be completely environmental. It is mostly a combination of multiple hits, common genetic variance combined together with environmental factors. Our goal is to be able to provide a diagnosis based on a common epigenetic modification. With that, we could provide children with behavioral therapies to help them improve their skills since the brain is still very plastic. Even if a child is genetically predisposed to autism, interventions can improve the outcomes, which is pretty amazing.</span>

<b>MH:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> How have you seen epigenetics change the healthcare field?</span>

<b>JS: </b><span style="font-weight: 400">Epigenetics is changing the healthcare field by escaping the conventional genetic determinism. Personal genomics ideas, like 23andMe, are great, but most people are at risks for common disorders like obesity, diabetes, and autoimmune diseases. Epigenetics is so powerful because we can change one’s lifestyle to lower the risks of the disease. I think that prenatal vitamins use is a great example of this because it can serve as a preventative measure in patients with common polymorphisms. Ultimately, if one is at higher risk for a disease, they have to make your own decision in the modification of their lifestyle. I can see personal epigenetics combined with using epigenetic markers as a way to change the healthcare field.</span>

<b>MH:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> Have you always been interested in the biotechnological side of research?</span>

<b>JS:</b><span style="font-weight: 400"> Great question. My generation would run sequencing gels and write out the base pairs by hand. The amount of data that we now are able to work with makes sequencing so important and exciting. Every time I turn around it is cheaper and faster to do. The challenge is that we get an immense amount of data that we have to handle. I do not know how to code myself, but many of my lab members have been able to pick it up. This is especially important in epigenetics because understanding what went into the biological sample is necessary to be able to analyze the data. My goal is to train students who are comfortable in both the science and the bioinformatics side. I think we really need the new generation of scientists feel comfortable with big data.</span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1738</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-11-10 03:44:01]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-11-10 03:44:01]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2019-02-12 17:58:30]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2019-02-12 17:58:30]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[aggie-transcript-interview-dr-janine-lasalle]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="autism"><![CDATA[autism]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="epigenetics"><![CDATA[epigenetics]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="genetics"><![CDATA[Genetics]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="neurodegenerative-disorders"><![CDATA[neurodegenerative disorders]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1739]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1553741382;s:7:"payload";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1224]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Epigenetics]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/aggie-transcript-interview-dr-janine-lasalle/epigenetics/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 03:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rmhull]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2018/11/Epigenetics.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1739</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-11-10 03:41:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-11-10 03:41:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2018-11-10 03:41:57]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2018-11-10 03:41:57]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[epigenetics]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1738</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2018/11/Epigenetics-e1541821403493.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2018/11/Epigenetics-e1541821403493.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:2233;s:6:"height";i:1440;s:4:"file";s:38:"2018/11/Epigenetics-e1541821403493.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:10:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-300x193.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:193;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-768x495.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:495;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:39:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-1024x660.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:660;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-large-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-830x535.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:535;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"sydney-medium-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-small-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-230x148.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:148;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sydney-service-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-350x226.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:226;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:16:"sydney-mas-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-480x310.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:310;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"Epigenetics-e1541821403493-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:11:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:2560;s:6:"height";i:1440;s:4:"file";s:15:"Epigenetics.jpg";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"medium_large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"Epigenetics-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:23:"sydney-large-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-830x467.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:467;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:24:"sydney-medium-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:23:"sydney-small-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-230x129.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:129;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sydney-service-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-350x197.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:197;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:21:"sydney-mas-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-480x270.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:270;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"Epigenetics-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[You might have to use more than a microscope, there’s more to genetics than what meets the eye: An interview with Dr. Gerald Quon]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/you-might-have-to-use-more-than-a-microscope-theres-more-to-genetics-than-what-meets-the-eye-an-interview-with-dr-gerald-quon/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 17:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/?p=2639</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>By Tannavee Kumar, Genetics &amp; Genomics 20’</strong>

<strong>Author’s Note: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400">As an undergraduate studying genetics and genomics and computer science, I wanted to interview a former professor to find out the steps he took in order to do computational research in the biological sciences. I was interested in finding out more about the growing field of computational biology and wanted to help shed light on a field to students that may be similarly interested. </span>

<b><i>Background</i></b>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">You received a Bachelors in Math, then a masters in Biochemistry, then a PhD in Computer Science; did you always know that you wanted to do research in biology? If so, what made you want to start off with a technical education rather than something traditional like biology or chemistry? If not, how did you come to discover applications of computer science in Biology even 15 years ago?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">No, I did not start off wanting to do anything related to biology. I started my undergrad thinking I would make computer games. How I kind of got into this was a week before my undergrad, I got an email from my university asking if I wanted to be a part of the first cohort of a bioinformatics program. I initially declined.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">As I was looking for my third internship in my co-op program, I had a friend who found a job for a professor in Toronto, and my friend asked if I wanted to work on this cool project about predicting how proteins fold into these 3D structures. I told him I don’t know anything about protein structures, but sure! It was a lot of fun.</span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">Is that what inspired you to pursue Biochemistry for further education?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">I think that first internship was very pivotal, because it really nurtured my interest in protein structures. When I finished my undergrad, I was kind of bored of computer science, which is why I thought I would do a PhD studying protein structures.</span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">How do you see life sciences research evolving and progressing in the coming years, given the inclusion of this new field?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">In my opinion, we will see more and more blurring of boundaries. In 25 years, there is going to be more undergraduate programs less defined by walls like “life sciences,” “chemistry,” and better recognition that everybody borrows knowledge and skills from many fields. It will be very difficult to do a life sciences degree without learning anything about math or statistics. Similarly, more people in traditional quantitative disciplines will want to take those classes in the life sciences. Essentially there will be fewer walls.</span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">How would undergraduates studying quantitative subjects, like mathematics, statistics, or computer science be made aware of the growing demand for such skills in the Life Sciences?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">The classic way to become introduced to such areas would be through coursework, internship with a company, or research with a professor. The last two ways are not very optimal. At the end of the day, in a standard undergraduate program, you have summers, and if you are ambitious you can try to do research during the school year. However, you can only do so many different kinds of internships before you graduate. If you did one every summer of college, and even two before hand, even that would not be sufficient for getting a nice, representative sample for all the things you can work on. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">That is where</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">universities need to do a better job of creating opportunities for students to engage with people from industry and research so that they don’t need 4-5 months to figure many essential things out. </span>

<b><i>Research and Beyond</i></b>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">Can you briefly describe some of the research that your lab does?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">We are currently working towards a few different directions. A large project at the moment is studying the genetics of mental disorders and neurodegeneration, for example we look at the genetics of Alzheimer’s disease, schizophrenia, autism, etc. Our main goal is to mechanistically understand how genetic variants associated with these mental conditions modify disease risk. Much of those mechanistic studies currently look at events that happen at the molecular level. This is great and very useful; however, since the majority of the research is geared at the molecular level we don’t have a good understanding of what variants do functionally at the level of the cell. How does it affect the functional properties of the cell, such as neuron electrophysiology? Or, how is the organization of the tissue affected? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Other areas we work on are on building better models to understand how cells are spatially  organized in the brain, as well as building models that quantitatively describe cell population behavior. We know that cells behave differently when put into different contexts. It’s of interest to build a model to predict what happens when you put together different kinds of cells in different combinations, orientations, or conditions. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Lastly, a third project being worked on is on the therapeutic end. We are essentially trying to identify the druggable region of the genome. There are a lot of computational problems in trying to determine what is druggable.</span><span style="font-weight: 400">                           </span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400"> </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400">How do you think the integration of the computational sciences has shed light on how biological processes are interconnected, and what do they make clear that a molecular approach may not be able to?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">In human genetics, computational models play a huge role in hypothesis generation. They do a good job leveraging big data, such as genomics, to prioritize which variants should be tested using molecular approaches, for example, when molecular approaches are costly or too slow to systematically test many variants across a genome. The role of computation is parsing through the many possibilities that you can’t explore molecularly.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">For example, a study we worked on four years ago was to try and find a causal variant for obesity. Most human genetic studies only point to a region of the genome where causal variants might hide, but don’t tell you exactly which one is the true causal one. When these regions are big, like hundreds of kilobases long, you need computational tools to identify the precise causal one to test experimentally. In that study, computational tools played the pivotal role of identifying the causal variant that was ultimately tested and shown to drive large changes in obesity risk.  </span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">How does computational research like your own lead to the progression of curated care in the health industry?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">At a superficial level, in some ways it accelerates some of the biomedical discoveries that are being done today. The obesity study is one example. If you didn’t have the computational resources, you would spend years and years trying to find the right variant. However, we found it relatively quickly with computation.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">For healthcare specifically, fields such as machine learning are revolutionizing care today. People from statistics, computer science, and math are working directly with clinicians and hospitals to develop highly accurate ‘digital pathology’ software, they help predict when patients will need to come into the hospital or whether they are high risk for a disease.  </span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">Oftentimes, conditions and diseases are misdiagnosed, which leads to inappropriate treatments. How would research in this area begin to remedy this common problem in the healthcare industry?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Most diseases are heterogeneous, which means that a group of people who are diagnosed with the same condition might actually have different underlying conditions, and need different treatments. Many computational approaches based on molecular and clinical data are being developed to identify more homogeneous groups of patients, to help achieve precision medicine. This allows for the most accurate prescription of medication and treatments. This is because these homogenous groups help identify the underlying disease phenotype which means access to better directed medication.</span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">During your time as a PhD student, you also “explored the application of models built from deconvolving gene expression profiles, for personalized medicine.” Can you go more in depth to how these models were built and how it can advance our ability to provide a more accurate prognosis to patients?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">During my PhD, we were trying to predict the prognosis of early stage lung cancer patients. If you are diagnosed with early stage lung cancer say stage 1B, clinicians have to make important decisions, such as how much e.g. chemotherapy to give you. If they give you too much, it will get rid of the primary tumor, but you will increase your risk of recurrence. But if you don’t give enough, you don’t get rid of the primary tumor. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Back then, fourteen year ago or so, genome expression profiling was just becoming popular. People were thinking maybe we can predict whether these stage 1B patients were going to be at high risk of recurrence or not. Our motivation for that problem was essentially to build a computational model to predict based on molecular signatures if they should be given extra therapy or not. That in itself is a hard problem. Additionally, before single cell sequencing was available, it was hard to take a sample of a tumor and only sequence the tumor cells. Often times you would have contamination of normal cells that would mess up the signatures you would get. We had to develop a computational method to extract out only the signatures due to tumor cells, and show that once you do that it is much easier to predict prognosis.</span>

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">Where do you think research will be in the next 10-20 years?</span></i>

<span style="font-weight: 400">We are going to see a lot more connections across more previously isolated fields. For example, with respect to human psychiatric genetics, a lot of focus right now is at the molecular impact of genetic variants, but in the near future I’d expect there to be much closer integration with clinicians to also study the impact on behavior, and with the experimental biologists to study the impact on brain development and organization. </span>

&nbsp;

<i><span style="font-weight: 400">***Special thanks to Dr. Gerald Quon for this interview</span></i>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2639</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-02-22 10:18:36]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-02-22 17:18:36]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-08-23 23:09:07]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-08-24 06:09:07]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[you-might-have-to-use-more-than-a-microscope-theres-more-to-genetics-than-what-meets-the-eye-an-interview-with-dr-gerald-quon]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="genetics"><![CDATA[Genetics]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="genetics-2"><![CDATA[genetics]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="interview"><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2642]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1170]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_show_first_featured_image]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fimg_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fimg_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_portfolio_width_100]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_video]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_image_rollover_icons]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_link_icon_url]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_links_target]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_related_posts]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_share_box]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_pagination]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_author_info]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_comments]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wooslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_revslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_elasticslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider_position]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_avada_rev_styles]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fallback]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_demo_slider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_main_top_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_main_bottom_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_hundredp_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_header]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_opacity]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_displayed_menu]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_footer]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_copyright]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_footer_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_layout]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_breadcrumbs_search_bar]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text_alignment]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_text]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text_size]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_line_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_subheader]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_subheader_text_size]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_font_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_mobile_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_borders_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_retina]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bg_parallax]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[fusion_builder_status]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-2_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-3_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-4_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-5_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[dna-1903318]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/you-might-have-to-use-more-than-a-microscope-theres-more-to-genetics-than-what-meets-the-eye-an-interview-with-dr-gerald-quon/dna-1903318/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 17:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/02/dna-1903318.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2640</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-02-22 10:16:36]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-02-22 17:16:36]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-02-22 10:16:36]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-02-22 17:16:36]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[dna-1903318]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>2639</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/02/dna-1903318-e1582391862354.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020/02/dna-1903318-e1582391862354.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1675;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:38:"2020/02/dna-1903318-e1582391862354.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:10:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-300x193.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:193;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-768x495.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:495;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:39:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-1024x660.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:660;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-large-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-830x535.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:535;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"sydney-medium-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-small-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-230x148.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:148;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sydney-service-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-350x226.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:226;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:16:"sydney-mas-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-480x309.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:309;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"dna-1903318-e1582391862354-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:11:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:15:"dna-1903318.jpg";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"medium_large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"dna-1903318-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:23:"sydney-large-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-830x467.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:467;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:24:"sydney-medium-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:23:"sydney-small-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-230x129.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:129;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sydney-service-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-350x197.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:197;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:21:"sydney-mas-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-480x270.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:270;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"dna-1903318-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Image from iOS]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/you-might-have-to-use-more-than-a-microscope-theres-more-to-genetics-than-what-meets-the-eye-an-interview-with-dr-gerald-quon/image-from-ios/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 17:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/02/Image-from-iOS.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2642</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-02-22 10:39:09]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-02-22 17:39:09]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-02-22 10:39:09]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-02-22 17:39:09]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[image-from-ios]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>2639</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/02/Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020/02/Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1584;s:6:"height";i:1022;s:4:"file";s:41:"2020/02/Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:10:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-300x194.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:194;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-768x496.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:496;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:42:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-1024x661.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:661;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-large-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-830x536.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:536;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"sydney-medium-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"sydney-small-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-230x148.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:148;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sydney-service-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-350x226.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:226;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:16:"sydney-mas-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-480x310.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:310;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:41:"Image-from-iOS-e1582393180868-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:13:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}s:14:"resized_images";a:2:{i:0;s:7:"500x383";i:1;s:8:"1000x766";}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:11:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1024;s:4:"file";s:18:"Image-from-iOS.jpg";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-300x160.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:160;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"medium_large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-768x410.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:410;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:27:"Image-from-iOS-1024x546.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:546;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:23:"sydney-large-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-830x443.jpg";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:443;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:24:"sydney-medium-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-550x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:23:"sydney-small-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-230x123.jpg";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:123;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sydney-service-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-350x187.jpg";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:187;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:21:"sydney-mas-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-480x256.jpg";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:256;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"Image-from-iOS-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Cryogenic Electron Microscopy: A Leap Forward for UC Davis]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/cryogenic-electron-microscopy-a-leap-forward-for-uc-davis/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/?p=3000</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>Photo originally published in <a href="http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pbio.1000092">Structural Studies of the Giant Mimivirus.</a> PLoS Biol 7(4): e1000092. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1000092">doi:10.1371/journal.pbio.1000092.</a> </em><em>License: <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5/deed.en">CC BY 2.5</a>.</em>

<strong>By Nathan Levinzon, Neurobiology, Physiology, and Behavior ‘23</strong>

<span style="font-weight: 400"><strong>Author's Note: </strong>The purpose of this article is to inform the UC Davis community about the arrival and use of a groundbreaking technology to campus. I hope to have provided a comprehensive introduction to Cryo-EM, information on Cryo-EM at UC Davis, and an example of how the technology is already being used to solve problems in biology on campus. I also aim to share my excitement regarding this technology in the hope that I inspire others to pursue this interesting and advancing field of study.</span>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">Cryo-electron microscopy, often abbreviated as “Cryo-EM,” is a version of microscopy that uses beams of electrons instead of light to illuminate cryogenically frozen samples. Because the wavelength of an electron is much shorter than the wavelength of light, samples can be imaged at mind-boggling resolutions. After the sample is captured in many orientations, the images are compiled in software to finally resolve a three-dimensional image. “If you want to imagine what it’s like to use this technology,” UC Davis Professor Jawdat Al-Bassam explains in an interview for the College of Biological Sciences, “think about walking into a museum, looking at a statue, taking pictures of it, and figuring out how to put those pictures together to get a three-dimensional picture. In essence, that's what we do with molecules. They are like small molecular statues, and we take images of them at a variety of angles and orientations. We combine these images to get a design plan for how these molecules are put together ” [1].</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">As a result of recent advances in technology and software, the progress in the resolution of Cryo-EM seems limitless. New microscopes on the market have brought the lowest resolution down to about two  angstroms—twice the diameter of a hydrogen atom—with even higher resolutions yet to come. Before 2010, scientists could achieve maximum resolutions of about four angstroms. This incredible and exciting variant of microscopy stands to shape the future of biological sciences. Dean of Biological Sciences Mark Winey says that “Cryo-EM is certainly part of the portfolio of technology that any campus like UC Davis should have,” and it's easy to see why [1]. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">One of the most advanced Cryo-EM microscopes on the market today is the newly released Glacios Cryo-Transmission Electron Microscope (TEM) by Thermo-Fisher. On the surface, the Glacios functions like any other TEM: A cryogenically frozen sample is prepared and shot with electrons that hit a camera in order to resolve a high-resolution, black and white image. What makes this microscope different, however, is its groundbreaking camera. The camera has a pixel size slightly smaller than the area that electrons interact with, which enables a high-speed electron detector to find the center of electron events with sub-pixel precision. The end result is a fourfold increase in resolution from older TEMs while simultaneously reducing aliasing, a sampling error caused by electron interference.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">With this microscope, researchers can examine life at the molecular level better than ever before. The closed-system design of the microscope ensures a safe and robust pathway through every step of microscopy, from sample preparation and optimization to image acquisition and data processing of up to twelve samples [2]. Its massive throughput is as impressive as its small footprint, allowing for it to be installed in labs with pre-existing infrastructure. Autonomous sample loading and lense alignment have made Cryo-EM faster and easier for both the budding and seasoned scientist. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">UC Davis has recently made a large investment of its own in Cryo-EM. On January 31, 2020, the College of Biological Sciences celebrated the ribbon-cutting for their own ThermoFisher Scientific Glacios Cryo-Transmission Electron Microscope, outfitted with a Gatan K3 direct detector camera. Festivities were short-lived, however, because labs were already in line to use this new machine. Researchers at Professor Al-Bassam’s lab were some of the first to use this microscope while studying kinesin, a motor protein found in eukaryotic cells. By utilizing Cryo-EM to resolve the structure of kinesin, they concluded that kinesin’s tails open a part of the motor that encapsulates ATP, slowing the movement of these motors and allowing kinesin to cluster and work together. With this new microscope in hand, these researchers are now able to unravel the functions of kinesin and how it interacts with other kinesin to move and group. The complete paper discussing the binding between kinesin tail and motor domains and its function in microtubule sliding can be found in the January 2020 edition of eLife [3]. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Cryo-EM has never been easier, safer, and more accessible to use UC Davis. With the purchase of the Glacios, UC Davis has made itself ready to introduce a new generation of researchers to the field of modern biology. Resolutions that were thought impossible ten years ago are now a reality, and new advancements continue to push the bounds at which samples can be imaged at. With the quickening pace of advancements in Cryo-EM, there is no telling what mysteries researchers at UC Davis will uncover next.</span>

&nbsp;

<strong>References</strong>
<ol>
 	<li>Slipher, David, et al. “CRYO EM: Unleashing the Future of Biology at UC Davis.” UC Davis College of Biological Sciences, 31 Jan. 2020, biology.ucdavis.edu/cryo-em. Accessed 23 Mar. 2020.</li>
 	<li>“Cryo TEM: Cryo-EM.” Thermo Fisher Scientific - US, www.thermofisher.com/us/en/home/electron-microscopy/products/transmission-electron-microscopes/glacios-cryo-tem.html.</li>
 	<li>Bodrug, Tatyana, et al. “The Kinesin-5 Tail Domain Directly Modulates the Mechanochemical Cycle of the Motor Domain for Anti-Parallel Microtubule Sliding.” ELife, vol. 9, 2020, doi:10.7554/elife.51131.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3000</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-22 12:51:36]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-22 19:51:36]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-05-22 12:51:36]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-22 19:51:36]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[cryogenic-electron-microscopy-a-leap-forward-for-uc-davis]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="cryo"><![CDATA[cryo]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="cryoelectron"><![CDATA[cryoelectron]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="microscope"><![CDATA[microscope]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="microscopy"><![CDATA[microscopy]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3001]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2012]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio.1000092.g005]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/cryogenic-electron-microscopy-a-leap-forward-for-uc-davis/cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_giant_mimivirus_-_journal-pbio-1000092-g005/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/05/Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005.png</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3001</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-22 12:38:16]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-22 19:38:16]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-05-22 12:45:18]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-22 19:45:18]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_giant_mimivirus_-_journal-pbio-1000092-g005]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>3000</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/05/Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998.png]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020/05/Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998.png]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:2126;s:6:"height";i:1371;s:4:"file";s:102:"2020/05/Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998.png";s:5:"sizes";a:10:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-150x150.png";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-300x193.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:193;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-768x495.png";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:495;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:103:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-1024x660.png";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:660;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:18:"sydney-large-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-830x535.png";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:535;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:19:"sydney-medium-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-550x400.png";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:18:"sydney-small-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-230x148.png";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:148;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:20:"sydney-service-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-350x226.png";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:226;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:16:"sydney-mas-thumb";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-480x310.png";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:310;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:102:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-e1590176609998-272x182.png";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:13:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}s:14:"resized_images";a:2:{i:0;s:7:"500x383";i:1;s:8:"1000x766";}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:11:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:2126;s:6:"height";i:1524;s:4:"file";s:79:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005.png";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-150x150.png";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-300x215.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:215;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:17:"medium_large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-768x551.png";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:551;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:10:"large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:88:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-1024x734.png";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:734;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:23:"sydney-large-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-830x595.png";s:5:"width";i:830;s:6:"height";i:595;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:24:"sydney-medium-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-550x400.png";s:5:"width";i:550;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:23:"sydney-small-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-230x165.png";s:5:"width";i:230;s:6:"height";i:165;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:25:"sydney-service-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-350x251.png";s:5:"width";i:350;s:6:"height";i:251;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:21:"sydney-mas-thumb-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-480x344.png";s:5:"width";i:480;s:6:"height";i:344;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:87:"Cryoelectron_microscopy_of_the_Giant_Mimivirus_-_journal.pbio_.1000092.g005-272x182.png";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[A Dive into a Key Player of Learning and Memory: An Interview with Dr. Karen Zito]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/a-dive-into-a-key-player-of-learning-and-memory-an-interview-with-dr-karen-zito/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 23:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/?p=3534</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=1325252">Image</a> by MethoxyRoxy - Own work, CC BY-SA 2.5</em>

<strong>By: Neha Madugala, Neurology, Physiology, and Behavior, ‘21</strong>

<b>Author’s Note</b><span style="font-weight: 400">: After writing a paper for the Aggie Transcript on the basics of dendritic spines, I wanted to take a more in-depth look at current research in this field by interviewing the UC Davis professor Karen Zito, who is actively involved in dendritic spine research. While there are still a lot of questions that remain unanswered within this field, I was interested in learning more about current theories and hypotheses that address some of these questions. Special thanks to Professor Zito for talking to us about her research. It was an honor to talk to her about her passion and knowledge for this exciting and complex field. </span>

&nbsp;

<b>Preface</b><span style="font-weight: 400">: This interview is a follow-up to an original literature review on dendritic spines. For a more in-depth look at general information on dendritic spines, check out </span><a href="https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/the-role-of-dendritic-spine-density-in-neuropsychiatric-and-learning-disorders/"><span style="font-weight: 400">this article</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">. </span>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">Neha Madugala (NM): Can you briefly describe some of the research that your lab does? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Dr. Karen Zito (KZ): My lab is interested in learning and memory. Specifically, we want to understand the molecular and cellular changes that occur in the brain as we learn. Our brain consists of circuits, connecting groups of neurons, and the function of these circuits allows us to learn new skills and form new memories. Notably, the strength of connections between specific neurons in these circuits can change during learning, or neurons can form new connections with other neurons to support learning. We have been mainly focusing on structural changes in the brain. This includes questions such as the following: How do neurons change in structure during learning? How do new circuit connections get made? What are the molecular signaling pathways that are activated to allow these changes to happen while learning? How is the plasticity of neural circuits altered with age or due to disease?</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: What are dendritic spines? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: Dendritic spines are microscopic protrusions from dendrites of neurons and are often the site of change associated with learning. Axons of one neuron will synapse onto the dendritic spine of another neuron. Spines will grow and retract during development and synapses between a spine and axon will form during learning, forming complex circuits that allow us to do intricate tasks such as playing the piano. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: Transient spines only last a couple of days. What role do they play in learning? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: One hypothesis for the function of transient spines is that they exist to sample the environment, allowing the brain to speed up its ability to find the right connections required for learning. Thus, the rapid growth and retraction of transient spines in the brain helps our neurons find the right connections required to form the new neural circuits by sampling many more connections and narrowing in on the right ones. For instance, in a past study on songbirds, researchers found that baby songbirds with faster moving transient spines were able to learn songs quicker than baby songbirds with slower moving transient spines. Once these transient spines find the right connection, they will transition from transient to a permanent spine to partake in a circuit that supports a new behavior, such as the songbird learning a new song.  </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: Can presynaptic neurons directly synapse onto a dendrite or only a dendritic spine?</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: Many neurons do not have spines at all. Spines are predominantly present on neurons in the higher order areas of the brain involved in learning, memory, perception and cognition. Spiny neurons are present in areas of the brain where neural connections are changing over time, or plastic — allowing the brain to learn, adjust, and change. Certain areas of the brain do not require a lot of change and, in some cases, circuit change may be detrimental to function. For example, we may not want to change connections established for movement of specific muscles.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: What is the difference between synapses that occur directly on a dendrite versus onto a dendritic spine?</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: Importantly, the molecular composition at synapses can vary widely between synapses, regardless of whether this connection occurs at a shaft or a spine. Therefore, it is difficult to name specific compositional elements always found at a spine versus a shaft. Inhibitory synapses, formed by GABAergic neurons, tend to be found directly on the shaft of dendrites. Glutamatergic neurons, which are excitatory, in the cerebral cortex tend to synapse on dendritic spines, but can also connect directly with the dendrite.  </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: All dendritic spines have excitatory synapses that require NMDA and AMPA receptors [1].</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> Are these receptors necessary for these spines to exist?</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: To my knowledge, we do not know the answer to this question. It is possible to remove these receptors a few at a time, and spines do not disappear. However, it is really hard to remove a receptor from a single spine and, if the receptors are removed from the entire neuron, it is often replaced with another receptor in a process called compensation. In order to test if this is possible, someone would have to knock out all genes encoding AMPA receptors and NMDA receptors, which is over seven genes, to see if spines still formed. Notably, if AMPA receptors are internalized, the spine typically shrinks, and if more AMPA receptors are brought to the surface, the spine typically grows. Indeed, the number of AMPA receptors at the synapse is directly proportional to the size of the spine. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: What drives spine formation and elimination when creating and refining neural circuits? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: There really is no definitive answer to this question currently, and many of those performing dendritic spine research are interested in answering these questions. Let’s first look at formation. One theory suggests that there are factors coming from neighboring neurons, such as glutamate or BDNF [2],</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> which promote spine formation. However, it is unclear which of these are acting </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">in vivo</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, in the animal. Also, spine formation is much greater in younger animals compared to older animals. That can suggest that the cells are in a different state when younger versus older. The cell can be a less plastic state where all the spines are moving slowly, seen in older animals, or more plastic states where all the spines are moving more quickly, seen in younger animals. Thus, there appears to be a combination of intrinsic state, or how plastic the cell is, and extracellular factors such as the presence of glutamate that dictates spine formation. Elimination is similar in that we do not really know the entire molecular signaling sequence that is driving it. It is a fascinating question for so many reasons. For example, when we are young we overproduce spines, and as we grow the spine density declines as our nervous system selectively chooses which connections to keep. Then, as adults, our spine density remains relatively stable. However, we obviously keep learning as adults, even though our spine density remains constant. One hypothesis is that, as a spine grows while learning, a nearby spine with no activity shrinks and eventually becomes eliminated. In fact, we have observed this phenomenon in our studies. Therefore, there may be some local competition between these spines for space. This keeps the density the same across most of the adult life span. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: Does learning drive the formation of synaptic spines or does synaptic spine formation drive learning? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: This may depend on the type of learning. Both have been observed. Studies have been done imaging the brain during learning. Some people have found an increase in new spine growth suggesting that learning drives new spine formation. Other people say they found the same number of new spine growth, but a greater amount of new spine stabilization, suggesting that learning drives new spine stabilization. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400">NM: It has been observed that some intellectual disabilities and neuropsychiatric disorders are associated with an abnormal number of dendritic spines when compared to a neurotypical individual. Is this related to the insufficient production of dendritic spines at birth or deficits in pruning? </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: Indeed autism spectrum disorders have been associated with an increase in spines. This could potentially be associated with an overproduction of spines or reduced spine elimination. Notably, the majority of neurological disorders resulting in cognitive deficits, such as Alzheimer’s disease, are associated with decreased spine densities. It is unclear if the spine numbers or brain function diminishes first, but much of the current research seems to suggest that the spines go away first, leading to the cognitive problems observed. In many disorders with too few spines, there is a normal formation of spines but excessive elimination. This is seen as Alzheimer and schizophrenic patients' spine density is relatively normal prior to disease onset. For Alzheimer’s specifically, some researchers suggest that the molecular release of the pathogenic amyloid beta peptide binds to molecules on the surface of the dendritic spine that drive spine loss. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">NM: How might dendritic spine research help in treating neuropsychiatric and neurodegenerative disorders?</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">KZ: Current research is looking at how to stabilize and destabilize dendritic spines. If we were able to manipulate the stability of these spines, we could potentially help rescue the stability of spines in patients with neuropsychiatric disorders, which could potentially lead to better therapies and outcomes. Understanding the pathways that control the stability of these spines will allow researchers to find targets for future therapeutic treatments.</span>

&nbsp;

<strong>Footnotes</strong>
<ol>
 	<li><strong><span style="font-weight: 400">Receptors that are permeable to cations. They are usually associated with the depolarization of neurons.</span></strong></li>
 	<li>Brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF): Plays a role in the growth and development of neurons.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3534</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-12-25 16:43:08]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-12-25 23:43:08]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-12-25 16:43:08]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-12-25 23:43:08]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[a-dive-into-a-key-player-of-learning-and-memory-an-interview-with-dr-karen-zito]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="dendritic-spines"><![CDATA[dendritic spines]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="neurobiology"><![CDATA[Neurobiology]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[911]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3535]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_show_first_featured_image]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fimg_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fimg_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_portfolio_width_100]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_video]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_image_rollover_icons]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_link_icon_url]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_links_target]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_related_posts]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_share_box]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_pagination]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_author_info]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_comments]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wooslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_revslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_elasticslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider_position]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_avada_rev_styles]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fallback]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_demo_slider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_main_top_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_main_bottom_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_hundredp_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_header]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_opacity]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_displayed_menu]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_footer]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_copyright]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_footer_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_layout]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_breadcrumbs_search_bar]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text_alignment]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_text]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text_size]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_line_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_subheader]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_subheader_text_size]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_font_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_mobile_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_borders_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_retina]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bg_parallax]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[fusion_builder_status]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-2_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-3_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-4_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-5_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1353]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Gyrus_Dentatus_40x]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/a-dive-into-a-key-player-of-learning-and-memory-an-interview-with-dr-karen-zito/gyrus_dentatus_40x/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 23:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blbahn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/12/Gyrus_Dentatus_40x.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3535</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-12-25 16:38:44]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-12-25 23:38:44]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2020-12-25 16:38:44]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2020-12-25 23:38:44]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[gyrus_dentatus_40x]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>3534</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2020/12/Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020/12/Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1344;s:6:"height";i:866;s:4:"file";s:45:"2020/12/Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:24:{s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-300x193.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:193;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:46:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-1024x660.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:660;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-768x495.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:495;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"portfolio-full";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-940x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:940;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:13:"portfolio-one";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-540x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:540;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:13:"portfolio-two";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-460x295.jpg";s:5:"width";i:460;s:6:"height";i:295;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:15:"portfolio-three";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-300x214.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:214;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"portfolio-five";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-177x142.jpg";s:5:"width";i:177;s:6:"height";i:142;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"blog-large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-669x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:669;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"blog-medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-320x202.jpg";s:5:"width";i:320;s:6:"height";i:202;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"recent-posts";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-700x441.jpg";s:5:"width";i:700;s:6:"height";i:441;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:22:"recent-works-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:43:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-66x66.jpg";s:5:"width";i:66;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:0;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-200x152.jpg";s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:152;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:1;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-400x305.jpg";s:5:"width";i:400;s:6:"height";i:305;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:2;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-600x457.jpg";s:5:"width";i:600;s:6:"height";i:457;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:3;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-800x610.jpg";s:5:"width";i:800;s:6:"height";i:610;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:4;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-1200x914.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1200;s:6:"height";i:914;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:5;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-200x129.jpg";s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:129;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:6;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-400x258.jpg";s:5:"width";i:400;s:6:"height";i:258;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:7;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-600x387.jpg";s:5:"width";i:600;s:6:"height";i:387;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:8;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:45:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-800x515.jpg";s:5:"width";i:800;s:6:"height";i:515;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:9;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:46:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-e1608939571442-1200x773.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1200;s:6:"height";i:773;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"1";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:15:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:1344;s:6:"height";i:1024;s:4:"file";s:22:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x.jpg";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-300x229.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:229;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"medium_large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-768x585.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:585;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-1024x780.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:780;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"portfolio-full-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-940x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:940;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"portfolio-one-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-540x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:540;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"portfolio-two-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-460x295.jpg";s:5:"width";i:460;s:6:"height";i:295;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"portfolio-three-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-300x214.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:214;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"portfolio-five-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-177x142.jpg";s:5:"width";i:177;s:6:"height";i:142;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:15:"blog-large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-669x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:669;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:16:"blog-medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-320x202.jpg";s:5:"width";i:320;s:6:"height";i:202;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"recent-posts-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-700x441.jpg";s:5:"width";i:700;s:6:"height";i:441;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:27:"recent-works-thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:28:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-66x66.jpg";s:5:"width";i:66;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"Gyrus_Dentatus_40x-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[How Poop is Fighting COVID-19]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/how-poop-is-fighting-covid-19/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 18:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wusarah]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/?p=4038</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<b>By Laura Gardner, Biochemistry and Molecular Biology ‘22</b>

<b>Author’s Note: </b><span style="font-weight: 400">With so much information in the media and online about COVID-19, I find many people get lost in, and fall victim to, false information. I want to reassure the Davis community with factual information on how Davis is fighting COVID-19. With UC Davis’ strong scientific community, I was curious what tools were being used to mitigate the spread of  COVID-19. In January 2021, I attended a virtual COVID-19 symposium called </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Questions about Tests and Vaccines </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">led by Walter S Leal, distinguished Professor of the Department of Molecular and Cellular Biology at University of California-Davis (UC Davis). In this symposium, I learned about Dr. Heather Bischel’s work testing the sewer system. This testing is another source for early detection of COVID-19. In combination with biweekly testing, I have no doubt that UC Davis is being proactive in their precautions throughout the pandemic, which made me personally feel more safe. I hope that this article will shed light on wastewater epidemiology as a tool that can be implemented elsewhere.</span>

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400">Dr. Heather Bischel is an assistant professor in the Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering at the University of California, Davis. Bischel has teamed up with the city of Davis through the Healthy Davis Together initiative to use wastewater epidemiology, a technique for measuring chemicals in wastewater, to monitor the presence of SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19 [6]. When a person defecates, their waste travels through the pipes and is collected in the sewer system. In both pre-symptomatic and asymptomatic individuals, their feces will carry the genetic material that indicates the virus is present. This is because SARS-CoV-2 uses </span><span style="font-weight: 400">angiotensin-converting enzyme 2, also known as </span><span style="font-weight: 400">ACE2, as a cellular receptor, which is abundantly expressed in the small intestine allowing viral replication in the gastrointestinal tract [1]. This serves as an early indicator of a possible COVID-19 outbreak and leads to quick treatment and isolation, which are important to stop the spread of the disease.  </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Samples are taken periodically from manholes around campus using a mechanical device called an autosampler. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">These autosamplers are lowered into manholes to collect wastewater flow samples every 15 minutes for 24 hours. Next, the samples are taken to the lab where they are able to extract genetic material and use Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) to detect the virus. Chemical markers that attach to the specific genetic sequence of the virus are added to the sample, which reacts to the COVID-19 virus by fluorescing visible light. This light is the signal that indicates positive test results. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">The samples are collected throughout campus, with a focus on residential halls. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">An infected person will excrete the virus through their bowel movements before showing symptoms. The samples are so sensitive that if even just one person among thousands is sick, they are still able to detect the presence of COVID-19 genetic material</span><span style="font-weight: 400">.  When a PCR test provides a positive signal, the program works closely with the UC Davis campus to identify if there has been someone who has reported a positive COVID-19 test. If no one from the building is known to be positive, they send out a communication email asking all the students of the building to get tested as soon as possible. That way the infected person can be identified and isolated as soon as possible, eliminating exposure from unidentified cases [4].</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">In collaboration with the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">UC Davis campus as well as the city of Davis, </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Dr. Bische</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> has implemented wastewater epidemiology throughout the community. Since summer 2020, Dr. Bische’s team of researchers have collected data which is available</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> online through the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Healthy Davis Together initiative</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> [4].  </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">In addition to being an early indicator, this data has also been used to determine trends, which can indicate if existing efforts to combat the virus are working or not [2]. Existing efforts include vaccinations, mask wearing, washing hands, maintaining proper social distancing, and staying home when one feels ill. UC Davis has implemented protocols including biweekly testing and a daily symptom survey that must be completed and approved in order to be on campus.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">Wastewater epidemiology has been implemented all over the world, at more than 233 Universities and in 50 different countries, according to monitoring efforts from UC Merced</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> [3]. This testing has been used in the past to detect polio, but has never before been implemented on the scale of a global pandemic. Lacking infrastructure, such as ineffective waste disposal systems, open defecation, and poor sanitation pose global challenges, especially in developing countries [2].  Without tools for early detection, these communities are in danger of having an exponential rise in cases.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400">Our work enables data-driven decision-making using wastewater infrastructure at city, neighborhood, and building scales,”</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> Dr. Bische stated proudly in her latest blog post [2]. These decisions are crucial in confining COVID-19 as we continue to push through the pandemic.</span>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4043 size-full" src="https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2021/11/unnamed-4-e1636153688422.png" alt="" width="512" height="168" />Summary of how wastewater epidemiology is used to fight COVID-19</p>
&nbsp;

<strong>References:</strong>
<ol>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Aguiar-Oliveira, Maria de Lourdes et al. “Wastewater-Based Epidemiology (WBE) and Viral Detection in Polluted Surface Water: A Valuable Tool for COVID-19 Surveillance-A Brief Review.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">International journal of environmental research and public health</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> vol. 17,24 9251. 10 Dec. 2020, doi:10.3390/ijerph17249251</span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Bischel, Heather.</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400"> Catching up with our public-facing COVID-19 wastewater research. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">Accessed August 15, 2021.Available from </span><a href="https://hbischel.faculty.ucdavis.edu/2021/08/02/catching-up-with-our-public-facing-covid-19-wastewater-research/%20research"><span style="font-weight: 400">H.Bischel.faculty.ucdavis</span></a></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Deepshikha Pandey, Shelly Verma, Priyanka Verma,et al. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">SARS-CoV-2 in wastewater: Challenges for developing countries</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, International Journal of Hygiene and Environmental Health,Volume 231,2021,113634, ISSN 1438-4639, </span><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheh.2020.113634"><span style="font-weight: 400">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheh.2020.113634</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">.</span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Healthy Davis Together. Accessed  February 2, 2021. Available from </span><a href="https://healthydavistogether.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400">Healthy Davis Together - Working to prevent COVID-19 in Davis</span></a></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">UCMerced Researchers. Covid Poops Summary of Global SARS-CoV-2 Wastewater Monitoring Efforts. Accessed February 2, 2021. Available from </span><span style="font-weight: 400">COVIDPoops19</span> <span style="font-weight: 400">(arcgis.com)</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> </span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Walter S Leal. January 13, 2021. COVID symposium Questions about Tests and Vaccines. Live stream online on zoom.</span></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4038</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-11-05 11:02:26]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-11-05 18:02:26]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-11-05 16:09:02]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-11-05 23:09:02]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how-poop-is-fighting-covid-19]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="biochemistry"><![CDATA[Biochemistry]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="biology"><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="campus-news-and-reports"><![CDATA[Campus News and Reports]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="covid-19"><![CDATA[covid-19]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="epidemiology"><![CDATA[epidemiology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="health-and-medicine"><![CDATA[Health and Medicine]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ucdavis"><![CDATA[ucdavis]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wastewater"><![CDATA[wastewater]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1218]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4039]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_show_first_featured_image]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fimg_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fimg_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_portfolio_width_100]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_video]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_image_rollover_icons]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_link_icon_url]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_links_target]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_related_posts]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_share_box]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_pagination]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_author_info]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_post_comments]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wooslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_revslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_elasticslider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_slider_position]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_avada_rev_styles]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_fallback]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_demo_slider]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_main_top_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_main_bottom_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_hundredp_padding]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_header]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_opacity]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_header_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_displayed_menu]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_footer]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_display_copyright]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_footer_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_layout]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_wide_page_bg_repeat]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repeat]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_breadcrumbs_search_bar]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text_alignment]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_text]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_text_size]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_line_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_subheader]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_custom_subheader_text_size]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_font_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_100_width]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_mobile_height]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_borders_color]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_retina]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bar_bg_full]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[pyre_page_title_bg_parallax]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[fusion_builder_status]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-2_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-3_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-4_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kd_featured-image-5_post_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[avada_post_views_count]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1731]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/how-poop-is-fighting-covid-19/uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wusarah]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2021/11/uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4039</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-11-05 11:00:43]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-11-05 18:00:43]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-11-05 11:00:43]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-11-05 18:00:43]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>4038</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2021/11/uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021/11/uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1238;s:4:"file";s:51:"2021/11/uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:25:{s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-300x193.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:193;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:52:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-1024x660.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:660;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-768x495.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:495;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:9:"1536x1536";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:52:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-1536x990.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1536;s:6:"height";i:990;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"portfolio-full";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-940x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:940;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:13:"portfolio-one";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-540x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:540;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:13:"portfolio-two";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-460x295.jpg";s:5:"width";i:460;s:6:"height";i:295;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:15:"portfolio-three";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-300x214.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:214;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"portfolio-five";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-177x142.jpg";s:5:"width";i:177;s:6:"height";i:142;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"blog-large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-669x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:669;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"blog-medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-320x202.jpg";s:5:"width";i:320;s:6:"height";i:202;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"recent-posts";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-700x441.jpg";s:5:"width";i:700;s:6:"height";i:441;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:22:"recent-works-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:49:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-66x66.jpg";s:5:"width";i:66;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:0;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-200x133.jpg";s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:133;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:1;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-400x267.jpg";s:5:"width";i:400;s:6:"height";i:267;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:2;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-600x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:600;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:3;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-800x533.jpg";s:5:"width";i:800;s:6:"height";i:533;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:4;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:37:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-1200x800.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1200;s:6:"height";i:800;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:5;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-200x129.jpg";s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:129;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:6;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-400x258.jpg";s:5:"width";i:400;s:6:"height";i:258;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:7;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-600x387.jpg";s:5:"width";i:600;s:6:"height";i:387;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:8;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:51:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-800x516.jpg";s:5:"width";i:800;s:6:"height";i:516;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}i:9;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:52:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-e1636135297387-1200x774.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1200;s:6:"height";i:774;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"5";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:18:"Canon EOS Rebel T6";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:2:"18";s:3:"iso";s:3:"100";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:5:"0.008";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:16:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1280;s:4:"file";s:28:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920.jpg";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-300x200.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:200;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"medium_large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-768x512.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:512;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:10:"large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:37:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-1024x683.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:683;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"1536x1536-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:38:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-1536x1024.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1536;s:6:"height";i:1024;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"portfolio-full-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-940x400.jpg";s:5:"width";i:940;s:6:"height";i:400;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"portfolio-one-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-540x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:540;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:18:"portfolio-two-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-460x295.jpg";s:5:"width";i:460;s:6:"height";i:295;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:20:"portfolio-three-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-300x214.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:214;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:19:"portfolio-five-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-177x142.jpg";s:5:"width";i:177;s:6:"height";i:142;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:15:"blog-large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-669x272.jpg";s:5:"width";i:669;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:16:"blog-medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-320x202.jpg";s:5:"width";i:320;s:6:"height";i:202;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:17:"recent-posts-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-700x441.jpg";s:5:"width";i:700;s:6:"height";i:441;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:27:"recent-works-thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-66x66.jpg";s:5:"width";i:66;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"uc-davis-g9c471b81a_1920-272x182.jpg";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[unnamed (4)]]></title>
		<link>https://aggietranscript.ucdavis.edu/how-poop-is-fighting-covid-19/unnamed-4-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 23:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wusarah]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2021/11/unnamed-4.png</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4043</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-11-05 16:07:31]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-11-05 23:07:31]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-11-05 16:07:31]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-11-05 23:07:31]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[unnamed-4-3]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>4038</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[https://aggietranscript.faculty.ucdavis.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/445/2021/11/unnamed-4-e1636153688422.png]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021/11/unnamed-4-e1636153688422.png]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:512;s:6:"height";i:168;s:4:"file";s:36:"2021/11/unnamed-4-e1636153688422.png";s:5:"sizes";a:14:{s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-300x98.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:98;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-150x150.png";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:13:"portfolio-one";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-512x272.png";s:5:"width";i:512;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:13:"portfolio-two";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-460x168.png";s:5:"width";i:460;s:6:"height";i:168;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:15:"portfolio-three";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-300x168.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:168;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:14:"portfolio-five";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-177x142.png";s:5:"width";i:177;s:6:"height";i:142;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:10:"blog-large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-512x272.png";s:5:"width";i:512;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:11:"blog-medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-320x168.png";s:5:"width";i:320;s:6:"height";i:168;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:22:"recent-works-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-66x66.png";s:5:"width";i:66;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}i:0;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-200x117.png";s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:117;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}i:1;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-400x234.png";s:5:"width";i:400;s:6:"height";i:234;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:20:"sow-carousel-default";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-272x168.png";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:168;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}i:2;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-200x66.png";s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}i:3;a:4:{s:4:"file";s:36:"unnamed-4-e1636153688422-400x131.png";s:5:"width";i:400;s:6:"height";i:131;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_backup_sizes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:11:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:512;s:6:"height";i:299;s:4:"file";s:13:"unnamed-4.png";}s:14:"thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-150x150.png";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:11:"medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-300x175.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:175;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:18:"portfolio-one-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-512x272.png";s:5:"width";i:512;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:18:"portfolio-two-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-460x295.png";s:5:"width";i:460;s:6:"height";i:295;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:20:"portfolio-three-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-300x214.png";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:214;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:19:"portfolio-five-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-177x142.png";s:5:"width";i:177;s:6:"height";i:142;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:15:"blog-large-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-512x272.png";s:5:"width";i:512;s:6:"height";i:272;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:16:"blog-medium-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-320x202.png";s:5:"width";i:320;s:6:"height";i:202;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:27:"recent-works-thumbnail-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:19:"unnamed-4-66x66.png";s:5:"width";i:66;s:6:"height";i:66;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}s:25:"sow-carousel-default-orig";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:21:"unnamed-4-272x182.png";s:5:"width";i:272;s:6:"height";i:182;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
	